<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="..\config\suzuki.xsl" ?><!DOCTYPE suzuki [<!ENTITY % sdatacharaents SYSTEM "..\config\sdatacharaents.txt">%sdatacharaents;]><suzuki><manual>
<section sectnbr = "8B">
<servcat sctnbr = "08" scnbr = "02">
<configtype typenbr = "0">
<servinfotype sitcode = "4">
<servinfo servinfosgmlid = "S5JB0E8204040" svcinfotypenbr = "06" svcinfoqualnbr = "01" page = "2" supplyoff = "0" modify = "0">
<title>
Inspection of Intermittent and Poor Connections
</title>
<ptxt>
Most intermittents are caused by faulty electrical connections or wiring. When a check for proper connection is requested in a diagnostic flow, perform careful check of suspect circuits.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
If any abnormality is found, repair or replace as a wire harness assembly.
</ptxt>
<list1 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
Poor mating of connector halves, or terminals not fully seated in the connector body (backed out).
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Dirt or corrosion on the terminals. The terminals must be clean and free of any foreign material which could impede proper terminal contact.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
However, cleaning the terminal with a sand paper or the like is prohibited.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Damaged connector body, exposing the terminals to moisture and dirt, as well as not maintaining proper terminal orientation with the component or mating connector.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Improperly formed or damaged terminals. 
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
Check each connector terminal in problem circuits carefully to ensure good contact tension by using the corresponding mating terminal included in the connector test adapter kit (special tool).
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
If contact tension is not enough, reform the terminal to increase contact tension or replace it.
</ptxt>
<servicetool>
<servicetoolitem id = "L8B0185">
<s-part>
(A)
</s-part>
<s-number num = "09932-76010">
09932-76010
</s-number>
<ptxt>
Connector test adapter kit
</ptxt>
</servicetoolitem>
</servicetool>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname = "I4RS0A820045.swf" width = "88.000mm" height = "102.661mm" ver = "01" gw = "156" gh = "274"/>
</figure>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Poor terminal-to-wire connection.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
Check each wire harness in problem circuits for poor connection by shaking it by hand lightly. If any abnormal condition is found, change the wire harness assembly or component parts with new ones.
</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname = "IYSQ01010028.swf" width = "88.000mm" height = "43.888mm" ver = "01" gw = "154" gh = "107"/>
</figure>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Wire insulation which is rubbed through, causing an intermittent short as the bare area touches other wiring or parts of the vehicle.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Wire broken inside the insulation. This condition could cause a continuity check to show a good circuit, but if only 1 or 2 strands of a multi-strand-type wire are intact, resistance could be far too high.
</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname = "IYSQ01820025.swf" width = "88.000mm" height = "42.787mm" ver = "01" gw = "110" gh = "104"/>
</figure>
</item>
</list1>
</servinfo>
</servinfotype>
</configtype>
</servcat>
</section></manual></suzuki>
