<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="..\config\suzuki.xsl" ?><!DOCTYPE suzuki [<!ENTITY % sdatacharaents SYSTEM "..\config\sdatacharaents.txt">%sdatacharaents;]><suzuki><manual>
<section sectnbr = "8B">
<servcat sctnbr = "08" scnbr = "02">
<configtype typenbr = "0">
<servinfotype sitcode = "6">
<servinfo servinfosgmlid = "S5JB0E8206018" svcinfotypenbr = "08" svcinfoqualnbr = "03" page = "2" supplyoff = "0" modify = "0">
<title>
Deployed Air Bag (Inflator) Module and Activated Seat Belt Pretensioner Disposal
</title>
<attention1>
<ptxt>
Failure to follow proper air bag (inflator) module and seat belt pretensioner disposal procedures can result in air bag deployment and pretensioner activation which may cause personal injury. The undeployed air bag (inflator) module and the inactivated seat belt pretensioner must not be disposed of through normal refuse channels.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
The undeployed air bag (inflator) module and the inactivated seat belt pretensioner contains substances that can cause severe illness or personal injury if the sealed container is damaged during disposal.
</ptxt>
</attention1>
<ptxt>
Deployed air bag (inflator) module and the activated seat belt pretensioner can be disposed of through normal refuse channels just like any other parts. For their disposal, however, the following points should be noted.
</ptxt>
<list1 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
The air bag (inflator) module and the seat belt pretensioner immediately after deployment &#x002F; activation is very hot. Wait for 30 minutes to cool it off before handling it.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Never apply water, oil, etc. to deployed air bag (inflator) module and the activated seat belt pretensioner to cool it off and be careful so that water, oil etc. does not get on the deployed air bag (inflator) module and the activated seat belt pretensioner.
</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname = "IYSQ01820095.swf" width = "88.000mm" height = "50.323mm" ver = "01" gw = "152" gh = "126"/>
</figure>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
After the air bag (inflator) module has been deployed, the surface of the air bag may contain a powdery residue. This powder consists primarily of cornstarch (used to lubricate the bag as it inflates) and by-products of the chemical reaction. As with many service procedures, you should wear gloves and safety glasses.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
When disposing of the deployed air bag (inflator) module and the activated seat belt pretensioner, be sure to seal it in a vinyl bag.
</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname = "I3JA01820119.swf" width = "88.000mm" height = "48.884mm" ver = "01" gw = "176" gh = "122"/>
</figure>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
When air bag (inflator) module and seat belt pretensioner have been deployed &#x002F; activated inside the vehicle which is going to be scrapped, leave them as installed to the vehicle.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Be sure to wash your hands with mild soap and water after handling them.
</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
</servinfo>
</servinfotype>
</configtype>
</servcat>
</section></manual></suzuki>
