<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="..\config\suzuki.xsl" ?><!DOCTYPE suzuki [<!ENTITY % sdatacharaents SYSTEM "..\config\sdatacharaents.txt">%sdatacharaents;]><suzuki><manual>
<section sectnbr = "1H">
<servcat sctnbr = "01" scnbr = "08">
<configtype typenbr = "0">
<servinfotype sitcode = "1">
<servinfo servinfosgmlid = "S5JB0E1801001" svcinfotypenbr = "03" svcinfoqualnbr = "01" supplyoff = "0" modify = "0">
<title>
Ignition System Construction
</title>
<ptxt>
The ignition system is an electronic (distributor less) ignition system. Especially a direct ignition system is adopted for J20 engine. They consists of the parts as described below.
</ptxt>
<list1 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
<emph etype = "bold">
ECM
</emph>
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
It detects the engine and vehicle conditions through the signals from the sensors, determines the most suitable ignition timing and time for electricity to flow to the primary coil and sends a signal to the ignitor (power unit) in the ignition coil assembly.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
<emph etype = "bold">
Ignition coil assembly (including an ignitor and an ignition coil)
</emph>
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
The ignition coil assembly has a built-in ignitor which turns ON and OFF the current flow to the primary coil according to the signal from ECM. When the current flow to the primary coil is turned OFF, a high voltage is induced in the secondary coil.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
<emph etype = "bold">
High-tension cords (for M16 engine) and spark plugs
</emph>
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
<emph etype = "bold">
CMP sensor (Camshaft position sensor) and CKP sensor (Crankshaft position sensor)
</emph>
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
Using signals from these sensors, ECM identifies the specific cylinder whose piston is in the compression stroke, detects the crank angle and adjusts initial ignition timing automatically.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
<emph etype = "bold">
TP sensor, ECT sensor, MAP sensor, MAF sensor, IAT sensor, knock sensor, wheel speed sensor (VSS) and other sensors &#x002F; switches
</emph>
</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
<ptxt>
For M16 engine, this ignition system does not have a distributor, it has two ignition coil assemblies (one is for No.1 and No.4 spark plugs and the other is for No.2 and No.3 spark plugs). When an ignition signal is sent from ECM to the ignitor in the ignition coil assembly for No.1 and No.4 spark plugs, a high voltage is induced in the secondary coil and that passes through the high-tension cords and causes No.1 and No.4 spark plugs to spark simultaneously. Likewise, when an ignition signal is sent to the ignitor in the other ignition coil assembly, No.2 and No.3 spark plugs spark simultaneously.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
For J20 engine, although ignition system does not have a distributor and high-tension cords but each cylinder has an ignition coil assembly (ignitor and ignition coil) and the secondary voltage which occurred in the ignition coil is sent to the spark plug directly. Also, the signal (s) are sent from the CMP sensor to ECM so as to control each ignition coil independently through the ignitor (in ignition coil assembly).
</ptxt>
</servinfo>
</servinfotype>
</configtype>
</servcat>
</section></manual></suzuki>
