<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="..\config\suzuki.xsl" ?><!DOCTYPE suzuki [<!ENTITY % sdatacharaents SYSTEM "..\config\sdatacharaents.txt">%sdatacharaents;]><suzuki><manual>
<section sectnbr = "5A">
<servcat sctnbr = "05" scnbr = "01">
<configtype typenbr = "0">
<servinfotype sitcode = "0">
<servinfo servinfosgmlid = "S5JB0E5100001" svcinfotypenbr = "01" svcinfoqualnbr = "01" page = "2" supplyoff = "1" modify = "0">
<title>
Precautions in Diagnosing Trouble
</title>
<list1 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
Do not disconnect couplers from TCM, battery cable from battery, TCM ground wire harness from engine or main fuse before checking the diagnostic information (DTC, freeze frame data, etc.) stored in TCM memory. Such disconnection will clear memorized information in TCM memory.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
For vehicle without engine diagnosis connector, diagnostic information stored in TCM memory can be cleared as well as checked by using SUZUKI scan tool or OBD generic scan tool. Before using scan tool, read its Operator&#8217;s (Instruction) Manual carefully to have good understanding as to what functions are available and how to use it.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
It is indistinguishable which module turns on MIL because not only ECM but also TCM turns on MIL. Therefore, check both ECM and TCM for DTC when MIL lights on.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
When checking TCM for DTC, keep in mind that DTC is displayed on the scan tool as follows depending on the scan tool used.
</ptxt>
</item>
<list2 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
SUZUKI scan tool displays DTC detected by TCM.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
OBD generic scan tool displays DTC detected by each of ECM and TCM simultaneously.
</ptxt>
</item>
</list2>
<item>
<ptxt>
For vehicle with engine diagnosis connector, using SUZUKI scan tool the diagnostic information stored in TCM memory can be checked and cleared as well. Before its use, be sure to read Operator&#8217;s Manual supplied with it carefully to have good understanding of its functions and usage.
</ptxt>
</item>
<c-change/>
<item>
<ptxt>
Not using scan tool (if equipped with AT monitor connector), the DTC stored in TCM memory also can be checked and cleared. DTC stored in the TCM memory is outputted by displaying DTC on digital display odometer with diagnosis terminal of monitor connector grounded. If no DTC is stored in TCM memory, DTC 0000 is outputted. If one or more DTCs are stored in TCM memory, they are outputted starting from smallest code number in increasing order. After all DTCs are outputted, all DTCs are outputted repeatedly.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Be sure to read 
<intxref refid = "S5JB0E0000006">Precautions for Electrical Circuit Service</intxref>
 before inspection and observe what is written there.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
TCM and&#x002F;or ECM replacement:
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
When substituting a known-good TCM and&#x002F;or ECM, check for the following conditions.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
Neglecting this check may result in damage to a good TCM and&#x002F;or ECM.
</ptxt>
</item>
<list2 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
All relays and actuators have resistance of specified value.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
MAF sensor, Manifold absolute pressure (MAP) sensor, TP sensor and fuel tank pressure sensor are in good condition. Also, the power circuit of these sensors is not shorted to the ground.
</ptxt>
</item>
</list2>
<item>
<ptxt>
Communication of ECUs, ECM, TCM, BCM, combination meter, 4WD control module (if equipped), ABS&#x002F;ESP&#174; control module, keyless start control module (if equipped), steering angle sensor (if equipped) and DLC is established by CAN (controller Area Network). For more detail of CAN communication, refer to 
<intxref refid = "S5JB0E5101004">CAN Communication System Description</intxref>
. Therefore, handle CAN communication line with care referring to 
<intxref refid = "S5JB0E0000005">Precaution for CAN Communication System</intxref>
.
</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
</servinfo>
</servinfotype>
</configtype>
</servcat>
</section></manual></suzuki>
