<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="..\config\suzuki.xsl" ?><!DOCTYPE suzuki [<!ENTITY % sdatacharaents SYSTEM "..\config\sdatacharaents.txt">%sdatacharaents;]><suzuki><manual>
<section sectnbr = "10H">
<servcat sctnbr = "10" scnbr = "08">
<configtype typenbr = "1">
<servinfotype sitcode = "0">
<servinfo servinfosgmlid = "S8T40AA810002" svcinfotypenbr = "01" svcinfoqualnbr = "01" supplyoff = "1" modify = "0">
<title>
Precautions in Diagnosing Trouble
</title>
<list1 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
To diagnose any trouble of CAN communication system, diagnosing the target control module &#x002F; sensor only is not enough for accurate diagnosis. Check communication conditions of overall system (including control modules and sensors related in CAN communication) and diagnose trouble putting those information together.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
It may be possible that CAN system has trouble because of fuse blown or low battery voltage. Before troubleshooting, check to make sure that fuse, battery voltage and charging system condition are normal.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Check to make sure that no equipment or option other than original parts is connected onto CAN bus. If any of such item is connected, disconnect it before troubleshooting.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
For troubleshooting of CAN communication system, be sure to refer to 
<intxref refid = "S8T40A0000002">General Precautions</intxref>
.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Even if any DTCs together with Lost Communication (Reception error) and&#x002F;or Communication Bus Off are displayed, start troubleshooting of CAN communication first.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
When disconnecting each control module connector in CAN troubleshooting, various DTCs will be detected. Be sure to clear DTCs in the following control modules after completing troubleshooting.
</ptxt>
</item>
<list2 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
ECM
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
TCM (A&#x002F;T model)
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
BCM
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
ABS &#x002F; ESP&#174; control module
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
4WD control module (motor-shift type 4WD model)
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Keyless start control module (keyless start model)
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
HVAC control module
</ptxt>
</item>
</list2>
</list1>
</servinfo>
</servinfotype>
</configtype>
</servcat>
</section></manual></suzuki>
