<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="..\config\suzuki.xsl" ?><!DOCTYPE suzuki [<!ENTITY % sdatacharaents SYSTEM "..\config\sdatacharaents.txt">%sdatacharaents;]><suzuki><manual>
<section sectnbr = "9L">
<servcat sctnbr = "09" scnbr = "12">
<configtype typenbr = "0">
<servinfotype sitcode = "1">
<servinfo servinfosgmlid = "S8T40A9C01001" svcinfotypenbr = "03" svcinfoqualnbr = "01" page = "2" supplyoff = "1" modify = "0">
<title>
Anti-Corrosion Treatment Construction
</title>
<attention1>
<ptxt>
Standard shop practices, particularly eye protection, should be followed during the performance of the following operations to avoid personal injury.
</ptxt>
</attention1>
<ptxt>
As rust proof treatment, steel sheets are given corrosion resistance on the interior and&#x002F;or exterior.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
These corrosion resistance steel sheet materials are called one of two-side galvanized steel sheets.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
It is for the sake of rust protection that these materials are selected and given a variety of treatments as described blow.
</ptxt>
<list1 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
Steel sheets are treated with cathodic electro primer which is excellent in corrosion resistance.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Rust proof wax coatings are applied to door and side sill insides where moisture is liable to stay.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Vinyl coating is applied to body underside and wheel housing inside.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Sealer is applied to door hem, engine compartment steel sheet-to-steel sheet joint, and the like portions to prevent water penetration and resulting in rust occurrence.
</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
<ptxt>
In panel replacement or collision damage repair, leaving the relevant area untreated as it is in any operation which does disturb the rust proof treatment will cause corrosion to that area. Therefore, it is the essential function of any repair operation to correctly recoat the related surfaces of the relevant area.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
All the metal panels are coated with metal conditioners and primer coating during vehicle production. Following the repair and&#x002F;or replacement parts installation, every accessible bare metal surface should be cleaned and coated with rust proof primer. Perform this operation prior to the application of sealer and rust proof wax coating.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
Sealer is applied to the specific joints of a vehicle during production. The sealer is intended to prevent dust from entering the vehicle and serves also as an anticorrosion barrier. The sealer is applied to the door and hood hem areas and between panels. Correct and reseal the originally sealed joints if damaged. Reseal the attaching joints of a new replacement panel and reseal the hem area of a replacement door or hood.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
Use a quality sealer to seal the flanged joints, overlap joints and seams. The sealer must have flexible characteristics and paint ability after it&#8217;s applied to repair areas.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
For the sealer to fill open joints, use caulking material. Select a sealer in conformance with the place and purpose of a specific use. Observe the manufacturer&#8217;s label-stand instructions when using the sealer.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
In many cases, repaired places require color painting. When this is required, follow the ordinary techniques specified for the finish preparation, color painting and undercoating build-up.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
Rust proof wax, a penetrative compound, is applied to the metal-to-metal surfaces (door and side sill insides) where it is difficult to use ordinary undercoating material for coating. Therefore, when selecting the rust proof wax, it may be the penetrative type.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
During the undercoating (vinyl coating) application, care should be taken that sealer is not applied to the engine-related parts and shock absorber mounting or rotating parts. Following the under coating, make sure that body drain holes are kept open.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
The sequence of the application steps of the anti-corrosion materials are as follows:
</ptxt>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Clean and prepare the metal surface.
</ptxt>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Apply primer.
</ptxt>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Apply sealer (all joints sealed originally).
</ptxt>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Apply color in areas where color is required such as hem flanges, exposed joints and under body components.
</ptxt>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Apply anticorrosion compound (penetrative wax).
</ptxt>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Apply undercoating (rust proof material).
</ptxt>
</s1>
</servinfo>
</servinfotype>
</configtype>
</servcat>
</section></manual></suzuki>
