<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="..\config\suzuki.xsl" ?><!DOCTYPE suzuki [<!ENTITY % sdatacharaents SYSTEM "..\config\sdatacharaents.txt">%sdatacharaents;]><suzuki><manual>
<section sectnbr = "1J">
<servcat sctnbr = "01" scnbr = "10">
<configtype typenbr = "1">
<servinfotype sitcode = "4">
<servinfo servinfosgmlid = "S8T40A1A14001" svcinfotypenbr = "06" svcinfoqualnbr = "01" supplyoff = "1" modify = "0">
<title>
Battery Inspection
</title>
<servinfosub id = "S8T40A1A14001001">
<title>
Common Causes of Failure
</title>
<ptxt>
A battery is not designed to last indefinitely; however, with proper care, it will provide many years of service. If the battery performs satisfactorily during test but fails to operate properly for no apparent reason, the following are some factors that may point to the cause of trouble:
</ptxt>
<list1 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
Accessories left on overnight or for an extended period without the generator operating.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Slow average driving speeds for short periods.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Electrical load exceeding generator output particularly with addition of aftermarket equipment.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Defects in charging system such as high resistance, slipping drive belt, loose generator output terminal, faulty generator or voltage regulator. Refer to 
<intxref refid = "S8T40A1A14002">Generator Symptom Diagnosis:M16A and J20A</intxref>
.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Battery abuse, including failure to keep battery cable terminals clean and tight or loose battery hold down.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Mechanical problems in electrical system such as shorted or pinched wires.
</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
<topic id = "S8T40A1A14001002">
<title>
Visual inspection
</title>
<ptxt>
Check for obvious damage, such as cracked or broken case or cover, that could permit loss of electrolyte.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
If obvious damage is noted, replace battery. Determine cause of damage and correct as needed.
</ptxt>
</topic>
</servinfosub>
</servinfo>
</servinfotype>
</configtype>
</servcat>
</section></manual></suzuki>
