<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="..\config\suzuki.xsl" ?><!DOCTYPE suzuki [<!ENTITY % sdatacharaents SYSTEM "..\config\sdatacharaents.txt">%sdatacharaents;]><suzuki><manual>
<section sectnbr = "1F">
<servcat sctnbr = "01" scnbr = "06">
<configtype typenbr = "3">
<servinfotype sitcode = "6">
<servinfo servinfosgmlid = "S8T40A1636005" svcinfotypenbr = "08" svcinfoqualnbr = "03" page = "2" supplyoff = "1" modify = "0">
<title>
Cooling System Flushing
</title>
<attention1>
<ptxt>
To avoid danger of being burned, do not remove radiator cap while engine and radiator are still hot. Scalding fluid and steam can gush out under pressure if cap is taken off too soon.
</ptxt>
</attention1>
<attention3>
<ptxt>
For detail of coolant specification, refer to 
<intxref refid = "S8T40A1631002">Coolant Description:N32A</intxref>
.
</ptxt>
</attention3>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Remove radiator cap when engine is cool as follows.
</ptxt>
<s2>
<ptxt>
Turn cap counterclockwise slowly until it comes to a stop. (Do not press down while turning it.)
</ptxt>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>
Wait until pressure is relieved (indicated by hissing sound), then press down on cap and continue to turn it counterclockwise.
</ptxt>
</s2>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
With radiator cap removed, run engine until upper radiator hose is hot (this shows that thermostat is open and coolant is flowing through system).
</ptxt>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Stop engine and drain coolant from radiator drain plug (1).
</ptxt>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Close radiator drain plug. Fill system with water and run engine until upper radiator hose becomes hot again.
</ptxt>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Repeat Steps 3) and 4) several times until drained liquid is nearly colorless.
</ptxt>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Close radiator drain plug (1) tightly.
</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname = "I8T401161005.swf" width = "88.000mm" height = "51.156mm" ver = "01" gw = "193" gh = "128"/>
</figure>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Remove reservoir cap (2) and reservoir (1).
</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname = "I8T401161007.swf" width = "88.000mm" height = "56.447mm" ver = "02" gw = "189" gh = "143"/>
</figure>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Empty reservoir of fluid and scrub and clean its inside reservoir with soap and water.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
Flush it well with clean water and remove water from inside, reinstall reservoir.
</ptxt>
</s1>
</servinfo>
</servinfotype>
</configtype>
</servcat>
</section></manual></suzuki>
