<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="..\config\suzuki.xsl" ?><!DOCTYPE suzuki [<!ENTITY % sdatacharaents SYSTEM "..\config\sdatacharaents.txt">%sdatacharaents;]><suzuki><manual>
<section sectnbr = "1A">
<servcat sctnbr = "01" scnbr = "01">
<configtype typenbr = "4">
<servinfotype sitcode = "4">
<servinfo servinfosgmlid = "S8T40A1144133" svcinfotypenbr = "06" svcinfoqualnbr = "02" supplyoff = "1" modify = "0">
<title>
DTC P1436: Speed Request
</title>
<attention2>
<ptxt>
After servicing, explain to the customer that it is necessary to regenerate the diesel particulate filter when diesel particulate filter warning light is lit in order to avoid unnecessary repairs.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
To regenerate the diesel particulate, customer must drive the vehicle until the light goes out, at a speed of 75 km&#x002F;h (47 mph) or higher for a while (max. 30 minutes).
</ptxt>
</attention2>
<attention3>
<list1 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
Conditions for applying fault finding procedures to stored faults:
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
The fault is declared present after the engine is started or following a road test.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
If the fault is present:
</ptxt>
</item>
<list2 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
Diesel particulate filter warning light is lit.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Specific driving requirement to regenerate the diesel particulate filter when driving.
</ptxt>
</item>
</list2>
<item>
<ptxt>
This DTC indicates whether a specific running request has been made in order to prompt a particulate filter regeneration.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Order of priority in the event of more than one fault:
</ptxt>
</item>
<list2 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
Firstly, deal with fault 
<intxref refid = "S8T40A1144132">DTC P1431: Clogged Diesel Particulate Filter Failures:F9Q</intxref>
 if it is present or stored.
</ptxt>
</item>
</list2>
</list1>
</attention3>
<servinfosub id = "S8T40A1144133001">
<title>
Troubleshooting
</title>
<table frame = "all" colsep = "1" rowsep = "1">
<tgroup cols = "1" colsep = "1" rowsep = "1">
<colspec colnum = "1" colname = "1" colwidth = "6.890in"/>
<tbody>
<row rowsep = "0">
<entry colname = "1" border-top = "1" border-bottom = "1" border-left = "1" border-right = "1">
<list1 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
Do not start diesel particulate filter after-sales regeneration with SUZUKI scan tool.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
Regeneration must absolutely be carried out when driving insofar as possible.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
The diesel particulate filter warning light is displayed on the combination meter to show a risk of the filter becoming clogged.
</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</servinfosub>
</servinfo>
</servinfotype>
</configtype>
</servcat>
</section></manual></suzuki>
