<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="..\config\suzuki.xsl" ?><!DOCTYPE suzuki [<!ENTITY % sdatacharaents SYSTEM "..\config\sdatacharaents.txt">%sdatacharaents;]><suzuki><manual>
<section sectnbr = "8B">
<servcat sctnbr = "08" scnbr = "02">
<configtype typenbr = "0">
<servinfotype sitcode = "0">
<servinfo servinfosgmlid = "S8T40A8200001" svcinfotypenbr = "01" svcinfoqualnbr = "01" page = "2" supplyoff = "1" modify = "0">
<title>
Precautions on Service and Diagnosis of Air Bag System
</title>
<attention1>
<list1 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
If the air bag system and another vehicle system both need repair, SUZUKI recommends that the air bag system be repaired first, to help avoid unintended air bag system activation.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Do not modify the steering wheel, dashboard, both front seat or any other on or around air bag system components.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
Modifications can adversely affect air bag system performance and lead to injury.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Be sure to follow the procedures described in this section. Failure to follow procedures could result in possible air bag system activation, personal injury or unneeded air bag system repairs.
</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
</attention1>
<list1 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
WARNING &#x002F; CAUTION labels are attached on each part of air bag system components (SDM, air bag (inflator) modules and seat belt pretensioners). Be sure to follow the instructions.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Many of service procedures require disconnection of &#8220;A&#x002F;B&#8221; fuse and air bag (inflator) module(s) (driver, passenger, side of both sides and curtain of both sides) from initiator circuit to avoid an accidental deployment.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Do not apply power to the air bag system unless all components are connected or a diagnostic flow requests it, as this will set a DTC.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
The 
<intxref refid = "S8T40A8204001">Air Bag Diagnostic System Check</intxref>
 must be the starting point of any air bag diagnostics. The 
<intxref refid = "S8T40A8204001">Air Bag Diagnostic System Check</intxref>
 will verify proper &#8220;AIR BAG&#8221; warning lamp operation and will lead you to the correct flow to diagnose any air bag malfunctions. Bypassing these procedures may result in extended diagnostic time, incorrect diagnosis, and incorrect parts replacements.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Never use air bag component parts from another vehicle.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
If the vehicle will be exposed to temperatures over 93 &#176;C (200 &#176;F) (for example, during a paint baking process), remove the air bag system components beforehand to avoid component damage or unintended system activation.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
When handling the air bag (inflator) modules (driver, passenger, side of both sides and curtain of both sides), seat belt pretensioners (driver and passenger), SDM, forward-sensor or side-sensor, be careful not to drop it or apply an impact to it. If an excessive impact was applied (e.g., SDM, forward-sensor and side-sensor are dropped, air bag (inflator) module is dropped from a height of 90 cm (3 ft) or more, seat belt pretensioner (retractor assembly) is dropped from a height of 30 cm (1 ft) or more), never attempt disassembly or repair but replace it with a new one.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
When using electric welding, be sure to disconnect air bag (inflator) module connectors (driver, passenger, side of both sides and curtain of both sides) and seat belt pretensioner connectors (driver and passenger) respectively.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
When applying paint around the air bag system related parts, use care so that the harness or connector will not be exposed to the paint mist.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Never expose air bag system component parts directly to hot air (drying or baking the vehicle after painting) or flames.
</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
<attention1>
<ptxt>
When performing service on or around air bag system components or air bag wiring, follow the procedures listed in 
<intxref refid = "S8T40A8206001">Disabling Air Bag System</intxref>
 to temporarily disable the air bag system.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
Failure to follow procedures could result in possible air bag system activation, personal injury or unneeded air bag system repairs.
</ptxt>
</attention1>
</servinfo>
</servinfotype>
</configtype>
</servcat>
</section></manual></suzuki>
