<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="..\config\suzuki.xsl" ?><!DOCTYPE suzuki [<!ENTITY % sdatacharaents SYSTEM "..\config\sdatacharaents.txt">%sdatacharaents;]><suzuki><manual>
<section sectnbr = "1J">
<servcat sctnbr = "01" scnbr = "10">
<configtype typenbr = "2">
<servinfotype sitcode = "6">
<servinfo servinfosgmlid = "S8T40A1A26001" svcinfotypenbr = "08" svcinfoqualnbr = "03" page = "2" supplyoff = "1" modify = "0">
<title>
Jump Starting in Case of Emergency
</title>
<servinfosub id = "S8T40A1A26001001">
<title>
With Booster Battery
</title>
<attention2>
<ptxt>
If vehicle is a manual transaxle model and has a catalytic converter, do not push or tow it to start. Damage to its emission control system and&#x002F;or to other components may result.
</ptxt>
</attention2>
<ptxt>
Both booster and discharged battery should be handled carefully when using jumper cables. Follow the procedure outlined below, being careful not to cause sparks.
</ptxt>
<attention1>
<list1 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
Failure to observe these precaution and procedure described below could result in:
</ptxt>
</item>
<list2 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
Serious personal injury (particularly to eyes) or property damage from such causes as battery explosion, battery acid or electrical burns.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Damage to electronic components of either vehicle.
</ptxt>
</item>
</list2>
<item>
<ptxt>
Remove rings, watches and other jewelry. Be sure to wear approved eye protection.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Be careful not to allow metal tools or jumper cables to contact positive (&#x002B;) battery terminal and any other metal on vehicle, because a short circuit could occur.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Do not connect jumper cable directly to negative (&#8211;) terminal of dead battery.
</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
</attention1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
For 4 A&#x002F;T model and 5 A&#x002F;T model, place select lever in &#8220;P&#8221; and apply parking brake before starting the engine.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
For 5 M&#x002F;T model, place gear shift lever in &#8220;Neutral&#8221; and apply parking brake before starting the engine.
</ptxt>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Turn off ignition, lights and all other electrical loads.
</ptxt>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
For battery that cell caps are equipped, check electrolyte level. If it is below low level line, add distilled water.
</ptxt>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Attach one of jumper cable terminals to positive (&#x002B;) terminal of booster battery and other terminal of same cable to positive (&#x002B;) terminal of discharged battery. (Use 12-volt battery only to jump start engine).
</ptxt>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Attach one of remaining jumper cable terminals to negative (&#8211;) terminal of booster battery, and other terminal of same cable to solid engine ground (such as exhaust manifold) at least 45 cm (18 in.) away from battery of vehicle.
</ptxt>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Start engine of vehicle with booster battery and turn off electrical accessories. Then start engine of vehicle with discharged battery.
</ptxt>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Disconnect jumper cables in exact reverse order.
</ptxt>
</s1>
</servinfosub>
<servinfosub id = "S8T40A1A26001002">
<title>
With Charging Equipment
</title>
<attention2>
<ptxt>
When jump starting engine with charging equipment, be sure the equipment is for 12-volt battery and negative (&#8211;) ground system. Do not use 24-volt charging equipment. Using such equipment can cause serious damage to electrical system or electronic parts.
</ptxt>
</attention2>
</servinfosub>
</servinfo>
</servinfotype>
</configtype>
</servcat>
</section></manual></suzuki>
