<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="..\config\suzuki.xsl" ?><!DOCTYPE suzuki [<!ENTITY % sdatacharaents SYSTEM "..\config\sdatacharaents.txt">%sdatacharaents;]><suzuki><manual>
<section sectnbr = "4F">
<servcat sctnbr = "04" scnbr = "06">
<configtype typenbr = "0">
<servinfotype sitcode = "1">
<servinfo servinfosgmlid = "S8T40A4601001" svcinfotypenbr = "03" svcinfoqualnbr = "01" page = "2" supplyoff = "1" modify = "0">
<title>
Electronic Stability Program Description
</title>
<ptxt>
Electronic Stability Program (ESP&#174;) has the following main functions.
</ptxt>
<list1 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
ABS &#x002F; EBD
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
ABS is that four wheel brake forces are independently varied with referring each wheel slip condition.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
EBD is that front and rear wheel braking forces are varied with referring loading distribution of the vehicle.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
ABS improves the vehicle stability, controllability and braking performance.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
For the details, refer to 
<intxref refid = "S8T40A4501001">ABS Description</intxref>
.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Traction control system
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
Traction control system function is that engine torque is controlled and brake is applied with referring wheel spin condition during vehicle starting and accelerating.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Stability control system
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
Stability control system is that engine torque is controlled and brake is applied with referring vehicle condition (over steering, under steering) during cornering.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Hill descent control (if equipped)
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
This function controls running of the vehicle on the down-slope stably at a constant low speed without tires being locked. The ESP&#174; control module activates the pump motor and each solenoid valves to operate to increase, retain or reduce the brake pressure applied to 4 wheels.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
This function enables the vehicle to run on the down-slope with such large gradient where the engine brake alone cannot provide enough deceleration, or where the road surface is rough or slippery, without driver&apos;s brake operation.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Hill hold control (if equipped)
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
This function prevents occurrence of creeping down which may occur at the driver&apos;s foot shift from the brake pedal to the accelerator pedal operation when starting the vehicle parked on the up-slope. The ESP&#174; control module activates each solenoid valve to operate to keep the brake pressure provided by the driver&apos;s brake operation. The vehicle can be stopped by this function for no more than 2 seconds.
</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
<attention3>
<ptxt>
ESP is a registered trademark of Daimler AG.
</ptxt>
</attention3>
</servinfo>
</servinfotype>
</configtype>
</servcat>
</section></manual></suzuki>
