<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="..\config\suzuki.xsl" ?><!DOCTYPE suzuki [<!ENTITY % sdatacharaents SYSTEM "..\config\sdatacharaents.txt">%sdatacharaents;]><suzuki><manual>
<section sectnbr = "0B">
<servcat sctnbr = "00" scnbr = "02">
<configtype typenbr = "0">
<servinfotype sitcode = "6">
<servinfo servinfosgmlid = "S8T40A0206044" svcinfotypenbr = "08" svcinfoqualnbr = "03" page = "2" supplyoff = "1" modify = "0">
<title>
Final Inspection for Maintenance Service
</title>
<attention1>
<ptxt>
When carrying out road tests, select a safe place where no man or no running vehicle is seen so as to prevent any accident.
</ptxt>
</attention1>
<servinfosub id = "S8T40A0206044001">
<title>
Seats
</title>
<ptxt>
Check that seat slides smoothly and locks securely at any position. Also check that reclining mechanism of front seat back allows it to be locked at any angle.
</ptxt>
</servinfosub>
<servinfosub id = "S8T40A0206044002">
<title>
Seat Belt
</title>
<ptxt>
Inspect belt system including webbing, buckles, latch plates, retractors and anchors for damage or wear.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
Check that seat belt is securely locked.
</ptxt>
</servinfosub>
<servinfosub id = "S8T40A0206044003">
<title>
Battery Check
</title>
<ptxt>
Check battery for damage, terminal corrosion and condition. 
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
If battery is equipped with built-in indicator, check battery condition by the indicator.
</ptxt>
</servinfosub>
<servinfosub id = "S8T40A0206044004">
<title>
Accelerator Pedal Operation
</title>
<ptxt>
Check that pedal operates smoothly without getting caught or interfered by any other part.
</ptxt>
</servinfosub>
<servinfosub id = "S8T40A0206044005">
<title>
Engine Start
</title>
<ptxt>
Check engine start for readiness.
</ptxt>
<attention1>
<ptxt>
Before performing the following check, be sure to have enough room around the vehicle. Then, firmly apply both the parking brake and the regular brakes. Do not use the accelerator pedal. If the engine starts, be ready to turn off the ignition promptly. Take these precautions because the vehicle could move without warning and possibly cause personal injury or property damage.
</ptxt>
</attention1>
<ptxt>
On A&#x002F;T vehicles, try to start the engine in each select lever position. The starting motor should crank only in &#8220;P&#8221; (Park) or &#8220;N&#8221; (Neutral).
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
On M&#x002F;T vehicles, place the shift lever in &#8220;Neutral,&#8221; depress clutch pedal fully and try to start.
</ptxt>
</servinfosub>
<servinfosub id = "S8T40A0206044006">
<title>
Exhaust System Check
</title>
<ptxt>
Check for leakage, cracks or loose supports.
</ptxt>
</servinfosub>
<servinfosub id = "S8T40A0206044007">
<title>
Clutch (for Manual Transmission)
</title>
<ptxt>
Check for the following.
</ptxt>
<list1 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
Clutch is completely released when depressing clutch pedal,
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
No slipping clutch occurs when releasing pedal and accelerating.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Clutch itself is free from any abnormal condition.
</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
</servinfosub>
<servinfosub id = "S8T40A0206044008">
<title>
Gearshift or Select Lever (Transmission)
</title>
<ptxt>
Check gear shift or select lever for smooth shifting to all positions and for good performance of transmission in any position.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
With A&#x002F;T vehicle, also check that shift indicator indicates properly according to which position select lever is shifted to.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
With A&#x002F;T vehicle, make sure that vehicle is at complete stop when shifting select lever to &#8220;P&#8221; range position and release all brakes.
</ptxt>
</servinfosub>
<servinfosub id = "S8T40A0206044009">
<title>
Transfer (Selectable 4WD)
</title>
<ptxt>
Check that transfer position indicator on instrument cluster turns on properly according to transfer switch position.
</ptxt>
</servinfosub>
<servinfosub id = "S8T40A0206044010">
<title>
Brake
</title>
<topic id = "S8T40A0206044011">
<title>
Foot brake
</title>
<ptxt>
Check the following:
</ptxt>
<list1 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
that brake pedal has proper travel,
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
that brake works properly,
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
that it is free from noise,
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
that vehicle does not pull to one side when brake is applied,
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
and that brake do not drag.
</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
</topic>
<topic id = "S8T40A0206044012">
<title>
Parking brake
</title>
<ptxt>
Check that lever has proper travel.
</ptxt>
<attention1>
<ptxt>
With vehicle parked on a fairly steep slope, make sure nothing is in the way downhill to avoid any personal injury or property damage. Be prepared to apply regular brake quickly even if vehicle should start to move.
</ptxt>
</attention1>
<ptxt>
Check to ensure that parking brake is fully effective when the vehicle is stopped on the safe slope and brake lever is pulled all the way.
</ptxt>
</topic>
</servinfosub>
<servinfosub id = "S8T40A0206044013">
<title>
Steering
</title>
<list1 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
Check to ensure that steering wheel is free from instability, or abnormally heavy feeling.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Check that the vehicle does not wander or pull to one side.
</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
</servinfosub>
<servinfosub id = "S8T40A0206044014">
<title>
Engine
</title>
<list1 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
Check that engine responds readily at all speeds.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Check that engine is free from abnormal noise and abnormal vibration.
</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
</servinfosub>
<servinfosub id = "S8T40A0206044015">
<title>
Body, Wheels and Power Transmitting System
</title>
<ptxt>
Check that body, wheels and power transmitting system are free from abnormal noise and abnormal vibration or any other abnormal condition.
</ptxt>
</servinfosub>
<servinfosub id = "S8T40A0206044016">
<title>
Meters and Gauge
</title>
<ptxt>
Check that speedometer, odometer, fuel meter, temperature gauge, etc. are operating accurately.
</ptxt>
</servinfosub>
<servinfosub id = "S8T40A0206044017">
<title>
Lights
</title>
<ptxt>
Check that all lights operate properly.
</ptxt>
</servinfosub>
<servinfosub id = "S8T40A0206044018">
<title>
Windshield Defroster
</title>
<ptxt>
Periodically check that air comes out from defroster outlet when operating heater or air conditioning.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
Set fan switch lever to &#8220;HI&#8221; position for this check.
</ptxt>
</servinfosub>
</servinfo>
</servinfotype>
</configtype>
</servcat>
</section></manual></suzuki>
