<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="..\config\suzuki.xsl" ?><!DOCTYPE suzuki [<!ENTITY % sdatacharaents SYSTEM "..\config\sdatacharaents.txt">%sdatacharaents;]><suzuki><manual>
<section sectnbr = "4A">
<servcat sctnbr = "04" scnbr = "01">
<configtype typenbr = "0">
<servinfotype sitcode = "4">
<servinfo servinfosgmlid = "S8T40A4104001" svcinfotypenbr = "06" svcinfoqualnbr = "01" page = "2" supplyoff = "1" modify = "0">
<title>
Brake Diagnosis Note
</title>
<servinfosub id = "S8T40A4104001001">
<title>
Road Test for Brakes
</title>
<ptxt>
Brakes should be tested on dry, clean, smooth and reasonably level roadway which is not crowned. 
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
Road test brakes by making brake applications with both light and heavy pedal forces at various speeds to determine if the vehicle stops evenly and effectively.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
Also drive vehicle to see if it leads to one side or the other without brake application. If it does, check the tire pressure, front end alignment and front suspension attachments for looseness. 
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
See diagnosis flow table for other causes.
</ptxt>
</servinfosub>
<servinfosub id = "S8T40A4104001002">
<title>
Brake Fluid Inspection
</title>
<topic id = "S8T40A4104001003">
<title>
Brake fluid leaks
</title>
<ptxt>
Check the master cylinder fluid levels. While a slight drop in reservoir level does result from normal lining wear, an abnormally low level indicates a leak in the system. In such a case, check the entire brake system for leakage. If even a slight evidence of leakage is noted, the cause should be corrected or defective parts should be replaced.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
If fluid level is lower than the minimum level of reservoir, refilling is necessary. 
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
Fill reservoir with specified brake fluid.
</ptxt>
<spec-sdm>
<sdm-title>
Brake fluid
</sdm-title>
<sdm1>
<sdm-condition>
</sdm-condition>
<sdm-value>
Refer to reservoir cap.
</sdm-value>
</sdm1>
</spec-sdm>
<attention2>
<ptxt>
Since brake system of this vehicle is factory filled with brake fluid indicated on reservoir cap, do not use or mix different type of fluid when refilling; otherwise serious damage will occur.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
Do not use old or used brake fluid, or any fluid from a unsealed container.
</ptxt>
</attention2>
</topic>
</servinfosub>
</servinfo>
</servinfotype>
</configtype>
</servcat>
</section></manual></suzuki>
