<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="..\config\suzuki.xsl" ?><!DOCTYPE suzuki [<!ENTITY % sdatacharaents SYSTEM "..\config\sdatacharaents.txt">%sdatacharaents;]><suzuki><manual>
<section sectnbr = "1A">
<servcat sctnbr = "01" scnbr = "01">
<configtype typenbr = "2">
<servinfotype sitcode = "1">
<servinfo servinfosgmlid = "S8T40A1121007" svcinfotypenbr = "03" svcinfoqualnbr = "01" supplyoff = "1" modify = "0">
<title>
Description of Electric Throttle Control System Calibration
</title>
<ptxt>
ECM calculates the throttle valve position on the basis of the completely closed throttle valve position data.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
The completely closed throttle valve position (signal voltage from TP sensor) of each system differs due to the individual differences of the throttle valve, the TP sensor and the APP sensor. As such differences must be taken into account for controlling the throttle valve, it is necessary to calibrate the completely closed throttle valve position data in ECM.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
After performing any one of the following service, it is necessary to calibrate the completely closed throttle valve position stored in ECM. 
<intxreftitleoff1 refid = "S8T40A1326005"><img src = "..\icon\intxreftitleoff.gif"/></intxreftitleoff1>
</ptxt>
<list1 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
Shutoff of backup power for ECM (i.e. disconnection of battery cable, replacement of battery, blown or removed &#8220;DOME&#8221; fuse or &#8220;B&#x002F;U&#8221; fuse)
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Replacement of ECM
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Clearance of DTC related to electric throttle control system (DTC related to electric throttle control system: P0607, P0122, P0123, P0222, P0223, P2101, P2102, P2103, P2111, P2119, P2122, P2123, P2127, P2128, P2135 or P2138)
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Replacement of throttle body assembly or accelerator pedal assembly with APP sensor
</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
</servinfo>
</servinfotype>
</configtype>
</servcat>
</section></manual></suzuki>
