<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="..\config\suzuki.xsl" ?><!DOCTYPE suzuki [<!ENTITY % sdatacharaents SYSTEM "..\config\sdatacharaents.txt">%sdatacharaents;]><suzuki><manual>
<section sectnbr = "4F">
<servcat sctnbr = "04" scnbr = "06">
<configtype typenbr = "0">
<servinfotype sitcode = "6">
<servinfo servinfosgmlid = "S8T40A4606002" svcinfotypenbr = "08" svcinfoqualnbr = "03" page = "2" supplyoff = "1" modify = "0">
<title>
Sensor Calibration
</title>
<attention2>
<ptxt>
If any DTC(s) other than C1075, C1076, C1077 or C1078 are detected, sensor calibration can not be completed. Repair the detected DTC first.
</ptxt>
</attention2>
<attention3>
<ptxt>
Steering angle sensor calibration is needed when battery, dome fuse or the steering angle sensor is removed.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
This sensor calibration can be done with&#x002F;without SUZUKI Scan Tool.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
When ESP&#174; control module and&#x002F;or yaw rate &#x002F; G sensor assembly is removed, sensor calibration is needed with SUZUKI Scan Tool.
</ptxt>
</attention3>
<servinfosub id = "S8T40A4606002001">
<title>
Sensor Calibration (Using SUZUKI Scan Tool)
</title>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Set steering wheel in straight-ahead position.
</ptxt>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Connect SUZUKI scan tool to data link connector (DLC) (1) with ignition switch OFF.
</ptxt>
<servicetool>
<servicetoolitem id = "L4F002">
<s-part>
(A)
</s-part>
<s-number num = "NNNNN-00024">
SUZUKI scan tool (SUZUKI-SDT)
</s-number>
<ptxt>
</ptxt>
</servicetoolitem>
</servicetool>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname = "I9T401821008.swf" width = "88.000mm" height = "53.625mm" ver = "01" gw = "148" gh = "135"/>
</figure>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Turn ignition switch to ON position and confirm that only any of DTC(s) C1075, C1076, C1077 and&#x002F;or C1078 is detected. If any other DTC are detected, repair the detected DTC.
</ptxt>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Park and level the vehicle with parking brake, stop engine with ignition switch ON, set steering in straight and without stepping on the brake pedal.
</ptxt>
<attention2>
<ptxt>
Hold the above condition in Step 4) to calibrate sensor correctly until sensor calibration is completed.
</ptxt>
</attention2>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Select menu &#8220;SENSOR CALIBRATION&#8221; under &#8220;Utility&#8221; of SUZUKI scan tool and calibrate sensor. Refer to scan tool operator&apos;s manual for further derails.
</ptxt>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
After completing the calibration, turn ignition switch to OFF position and disconnect SUZUKI scan tool from DLC.
</ptxt>
</s1>
</servinfosub>
<servinfosub id = "S8T40A4606002002">
<title>
Steering Angle Sensor Calibration (Not Using SUZUKI Scan Tool)
</title>
<attention2>
<ptxt>
When power is not supplied to the steering angle sensor by removing battery or fuse, steering angle sensor should be calibrated.
</ptxt>
</attention2>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Set steering wheel in straight-ahead position.
</ptxt>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Connect battery terminals and&#x002F;or fuse and start engine.
</ptxt>
<attention2>
<ptxt>
When power is not supplied to the steering angle sensor by removing battery or fuse, DTC C1075 is detected and SLIP indicator light (1) flashes.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
If DTC other than C1075 is detected, SLIP indicator light flushes and other indicator illuminate. In that case, repair the detected DTC first.
</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname = "I9T401460016.swf" width = "88.000mm" height = "42.689mm" ver = "01" gw = "174" gh = "104"/>
</figure>
</attention2>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Drive vehicle straight on level ground at 15 km&#x002F;h (9.5 mph) or above for few seconds without spinning wheels. And confirm that SLIP indicator light is OFF.
</ptxt>
</s1>
</servinfosub>
</servinfo>
</servinfotype>
</configtype>
</servcat>
</section></manual></suzuki>
