<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="..\config\suzuki.xsl" ?><!DOCTYPE suzuki [<!ENTITY % sdatacharaents SYSTEM "..\config\sdatacharaents.txt">%sdatacharaents;]><suzuki><manual>
<section sectnbr = "7B">
<servcat sctnbr = "07" scnbr = "02">
<configtype typenbr = "2">
<servinfotype sitcode = "0">
<servinfo servinfosgmlid = "S8T40A7220009" svcinfotypenbr = "01" svcinfoqualnbr = "01" page = "2" supplyoff = "1" modify = "0">
<title>
Precautions on Servicing Compressor Assembly
</title>
<attention2>
<list1 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
When replenishing or changing refrigerant and compressor oil and when replacing parts, make sure that the material or the part to be used is appropriate to the A&#x002F;C installed in the vehicle being serviced. Use of incorrect refrigerant or compressor oil will result in leakage of refrigerant, damage in parts or other faulty condition.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
When servicing the compressor, keep dirt or foreign material away from getting on or into the compressor parts and system. Clean tools and a clean work area are important for proper service.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
The compressor connection and the outside of the compressor should be cleaned before any &#8220;On-vehicle&#8221; repair or before removal of the compressor. The parts must be kept clean at all times and any parts to be reassembled should be cleaned with trichloromethane, naphtha, kerosene or equivalent solvent and dried with dry air. Use only lint free cloths to wipe parts.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
When compressor is removed from the vehicle for servicing, the oil remaining in the compressor should be discarded and new refrigerant oil added to the compressor.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
Minor repair procedures may be done on the vehicle without discharging the system. Major repair procedures require that the system be discharged of refrigerant.
</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
</attention2>
</servinfo>
</servinfotype>
</configtype>
</servcat>
</section></manual></suzuki>
