<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="..\config\suzuki.xsl" ?><!DOCTYPE suzuki [<!ENTITY % sdatacharaents SYSTEM "..\config\sdatacharaents.txt">%sdatacharaents;]><suzuki><manual>
<section sectnbr = "8A">
<servcat sctnbr = "08" scnbr = "01">
<configtype typenbr = "0">
<servinfotype sitcode = "0">
<servinfo servinfosgmlid = "S8T40A8100001" svcinfotypenbr = "01" svcinfoqualnbr = "01" page = "2" supplyoff = "1" modify = "0">
<title>
Precautions on Service and Diagnosis of Seat Belt
</title>
<attention1>
<ptxt>
If replacing seat belt is necessary, replace buckle and seat belt assembly together as a set. This is for the reason of ensuring locking of tongue plate with buckle. If these parts are replaced individually, such a locking condition may become unreliable. For this reason, SUZUKI will supply only the spare buckle and seat belt assembly in a set part.
</ptxt>
</attention1>
<ptxt>
Before servicing or replacing seat belts, refer to the following precautionary items.
</ptxt>
<list1 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
Seat belts should be normal relative to strap retractor and buckle portions.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Keep sharp edges and damaging objects away from belts.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Avoid bending or damaging any portion of belt buckle or latch plate.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Do not bleach or dye belt webbing. (Use only mild soap and lukewarm water to clean it.)
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
When installing a seat belt anchor bolt, it should be tightened by hand at first to prevent cross-threading and then to specified torque.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Do not attempt any repairs on retractor mechanisms or retractor covers. Replace defective assemblies with new replacement parts.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Keep belts dry and clean at all times.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
If there exist any parts in question, replace such parts.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Replace belts whose webbing is cut or otherwise damaged.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Do not put anything into trim panel opening which seat belt webbing passes through.
</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
</servinfo>
</servinfotype>
</configtype>
</servcat>
</section></manual></suzuki>
