<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="..\config\suzuki.xsl" ?><!DOCTYPE suzuki [<!ENTITY % sdatacharaents SYSTEM "..\config\sdatacharaents.txt">%sdatacharaents;]><suzuki><manual>
<section sectnbr = "7B">
<servcat sctnbr = "07" scnbr = "02">
<configtype typenbr = "2">
<servinfotype sitcode = "0">
<servinfo servinfosgmlid = "S8T40A7220002" svcinfotypenbr = "01" svcinfoqualnbr = "01" page = "2" supplyoff = "1" modify = "0">
<title>
Precautions on Servicing A&#x002F;C System
</title>
<servinfosub id = "S8T40A7220002001">
<title>
Handling HFC-134a (R-134a) refrigerant and specified compressor oil
</title>
<attention1>
<list1 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
Handle the HFC-134a (R-134a) refrigerant with care as follows. If not, it may cause severe injury such as blindness and frostbite.
</ptxt>
</item>
<list2 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
Avoid contact with skin and eyes by wearing safety glasses and gloves. In case of contact with skin or eyes, get medical attention.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Keep away from fire. High temperature may cause toxic gas. Therefore, take care of much room ventilation.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
The temperature above 40 &#176;C (104 &#176;F) in the refrigerant container may cause explosion.
</ptxt>
</item>
</list2>
</list1>
</attention1>
<attention2>
<list1 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
Do not expose bright metals to liquid refrigerant. Refrigerant combined with moisture is corrosive and tarnishes surfaces of bright metals including chrome.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Do not discharge HFC-134a (R-134a) refrigerant into atmosphere.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
The specified compressor oil of HFC-134a (R-134a) is highly hygroscopic.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
Keep internal parts of air conditioning free from moisture and dirt. When disconnecting any line from system, install a blind plug or cap to the fitting immediately.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
If pipes or hoses are replaced, replenish specified amount of compressor oil to compressor suction side referring to &#8220;Replenishing Compressor Oil&#8221; in &#8220;Operation Procedure for Refrigerant Charge&#8221;.
</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
</attention2>
</servinfosub>
<servinfosub id = "S8T40A7220002002">
<title>
Handling A&#x002F;C cycle part and tooling
</title>
<attention2>
<list1 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
When connecting hoses and pipes, apply a few drops of compressor oil (refrigerant oil) to O-ring.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Replace O-ring with new one once hoses, pipes and parts disconnected.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Route drain hose so that drained water does not make any contact to vehicle components.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
If pipes or hoses are replaced, replenish specified amount of compressor oil to compressor suction side referring to &#8220;Replenishing Compressor Oil&#8221; in &#8220;Operation Procedure for Refrigerant Charge&#8221;.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
When handling recovery and recycling equipment, be sure to follow the instruction manual for the equipment.
</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
</attention2>
<attention3>
<list1 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
Check local governmental regulations regarding working with refrigerator systems and its tooling.
</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
</attention3>
</servinfosub>
</servinfo>
</servinfotype>
</configtype>
</servcat>
</section></manual></suzuki>
