<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="..\config\suzuki.xsl" ?><!DOCTYPE suzuki [<!ENTITY % sdatacharaents SYSTEM "..\config\sdatacharaents.txt">%sdatacharaents;]><suzuki><manual>
<section sectnbr = "1F">
<servcat sctnbr = "01" scnbr = "06">
<configtype typenbr = "3">
<servinfotype sitcode = "1">
<servinfo servinfosgmlid = "S8T40A1631001" svcinfotypenbr = "03" svcinfoqualnbr = "01" page = "2" supplyoff = "1" modify = "0">
<title>
Cooling System Description
</title>
<attention1>
<list1 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
Be sure to check coolant level only on coolant reservoir (a translucent container) and add coolant only into the reservoir when replenishment is needed. Never remove radiator cap to check coolant level or add coolant, as doing so is very dangerous for the following reasons:
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
Coolant in cooling system may be extremely high in temperature, even exceeding the boiling point as it is under pressure. If radiator cap is removed in this condition, high-temperature and high-pressure coolant will instantaneously boil up and gush out; you could then be seriously scalded by hot coolant and steam. Furthermore, as coolant contains flammable anti-freeze material, coolant splashing over engine and fenders can start fire.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Be sure to check that engine coolant is cold before removing any part of cooling system.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Be sure to disconnect negative cable from battery before removing any part of cooling system.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
The coolant recovery system is a standard system, which allows part of coolant to flow from the radiator into the coolant reservoir when it is expanded by heat. When the cooling system cools down, the coolant in the coolant reservoir is drawn back into the radiator.
</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
</attention1>
<ptxt>
The cooling system consists of the radiator, coolant reservoir, water pump, cooling fan and thermostat. The radiator is of tube-and-fin type.
</ptxt>
</servinfo>
</servinfotype>
</configtype>
</servcat>
</section></manual></suzuki>
