<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="..\config\suzuki.xsl" ?><!DOCTYPE suzuki [<!ENTITY % sdatacharaents SYSTEM "..\config\sdatacharaents.txt">%sdatacharaents;]><suzuki><manual>
<section sectnbr = "1A">
<servcat sctnbr = "01" scnbr = "01">
<configtype typenbr = "4">
<servinfotype sitcode = "1">
<servinfo servinfosgmlid = "S8T40A1141007" svcinfotypenbr = "03" svcinfoqualnbr = "01" page = "2" supplyoff = "1" modify = "0">
<title>
Statement on Cleanliness and Care
</title>
<ptxt>
An automobile engine is a combination of many machined, honed, polished and lapped surfaces with tolerances that are measured in the thousands of an millimeter (ten thousands of inch).
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
Accordingly, when any internal engine parts are serviced, care and cleanliness are important.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
It should be understood that proper cleaning and protection of machined surfaces and friction areas is part of the repair procedure. This is considered standard shop practice even if not specifically stated.
</ptxt>
<list1 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
A liberal coating of engine oil should be applied to friction areas during assembly to protect and lubricate the surfaces on initial operation.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Whenever valve train components, pistons, piston rings, connecting rods, rod bearings, and crankshaft journal bearings are removed for service, they should be retained in order.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
At the time of installation, they should be installed in the same locations and with the same mating surfaces as when removed.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Battery cables should be disconnected before any major work is performed on the engine.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
Failure to disconnect cables may result in damage to wire harness or other electrical parts.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
The four cylinders of the engine are identified by numbers; No.1 (1), No.2 (2), No.3 (3) and No.4 (4) as counted from flywheel side to crankshaft pulley side.
</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname = "I5JB0B110001.swf" width = "88.000mm" height = "73.733mm" ver = "01" gw = "151" gh = "192"/>
</figure>
</servinfo>
</servinfotype>
</configtype>
</servcat>
</section></manual></suzuki>
