<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="..\config\suzuki.xsl" ?><!DOCTYPE suzuki [<!ENTITY % sdatacharaents SYSTEM "..\config\sdatacharaents.txt">%sdatacharaents;]><suzuki><manual>
<section sectnbr = "8B">
<servcat sctnbr = "08" scnbr = "02">
<configtype typenbr = "0">
<servinfotype sitcode = "6">
<servinfo servinfosgmlid = "S6JB0B8206008" svcinfotypenbr = "08" svcinfoqualnbr = "03" page = "2" supplyoff = "1" modify = "0">
<title>
Passenger Air Bag (Inflator) Module Inspection
</title>
<ptxt>
<intxrefpoff refid = "S6JB0B8206007">Passenger Air Bag (Inflator) Module Removal and Installation</intxrefpoff>
</ptxt>
<attention1>
<list1 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
Never measure resistance of passenger air bag (inflator) module or disassemble it. Otherwise personal injury may result.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Never attempt to disassemble or repair the passenger air bag (inflator) module. If any abnormality is found, be sure to replace it with new one as an assembly.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Be sure to read 
<intxref refid = "S6JB0B8200001">Precautions on Service and Diagnosis of Air Bag System</intxref>
, 
<intxref refid = "S6JB0B8200002">Precautions on Handling and Storage of Air Bag System Components</intxref>
 and 
<intxref refid = "S6JB0B8200003">Precautions on Disposal of Air Bag and Seat Belt Pretensioner</intxref>
 before starting to work and observe every precaution during work. Neglecting them may result in personal injury or undeployment of the air bag when necessary.
</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
</attention1>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname = "I5JB0A820084.swf" width = "88.000mm" height = "47.628mm" ver = "02" gw = "189" gh = "118"/>
</figure>
<attention2>
<ptxt>
If air bag (Inflator) module was dropped from a height of 90 cm (3 ft) or more, it should be replaced.
</ptxt>
</attention2>
<ptxt>
Check air bag (inflator) module appearance visually for the following symptoms and if any one of them is found, replace with a new one.
</ptxt>
<list1 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
Air bag has deployed.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Wire harness or connector is damaged.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Air bag (inflator) module is damaged or a strong impact was applied to it.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Bend or deformity of air bag (inflator) module bracket.
</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
</servinfo>
</servinfotype>
</configtype>
</servcat>
</section></manual></suzuki>
