<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="..\config\suzuki.xsl" ?><!DOCTYPE suzuki [<!ENTITY % sdatacharaents SYSTEM "..\config\sdatacharaents.txt">%sdatacharaents;]><suzuki><manual>
<section sectnbr = "8B">
<servcat sctnbr = "08" scnbr = "02">
<configtype typenbr = "0">
<servinfotype sitcode = "6">
<servinfo servinfosgmlid = "S6JB0B8206017" svcinfotypenbr = "08" svcinfoqualnbr = "03" page = "2" supplyoff = "1" modify = "0">
<title>
Air Bag (Inflator) Module and Seat Belt Pretensioner Disposal
</title>
<attention1>
<ptxt>
Failure to follow proper air bag (inflator) module and seat belt pretensioner disposal procedures can result in air bag deployment and pretensioner activation which may cause personal injury. Do not dispose of live (undeployed) air bag (inflator) modules and seat belt pretensioners. Because undeployed air bag (inflator) module &#x002F; inactivated seat belt pretensioner must not be disposed of through normal refuse channels. Undeployed air bag (inflator) module and inactivated seat belt pretensioner contain substances that can cause severe illness or personal injury if sealed container is damaged during disposal.
</ptxt>
</attention1>
<ptxt>
Air bag (inflator) module &#x002F; seat belt pretensioner can be deployed &#x002F; activated inside or outside of vehicle. Deployment &#x002F; Activation method used depends upon final disposition of vehicle. Review the following instructions in order to determine which will work best in a given situation.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
Deployment &#x002F; Activation Outside of Vehicle: When you intend to return the vehicle to service, deploy the air bag (inflator) module(s) and&#x002F;or activate seat belt pretensioner(s) outside of the vehicle.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
Deployment &#x002F; Activation Inside of Vehicle: When the vehicle will be destroyed, or salvaged for component parts, deploy the air bag module(s) and&#x002F;or activate seat belt pretensioner(s) installed on vehicle.
</ptxt>
<attention1>
<ptxt>
The following precautions must be observed for this work. Failure to observe any of them may result in personal injury.
</ptxt>
<list1 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
Procedure should be followed strictly as described here.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Be sure to read 
<intxref refid = "S6JB0B8200001">Precautions on Service and Diagnosis of Air Bag System</intxref>
 beforehand.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
To avoid accidental deployment &#x002F; activation, this work should be performed by no more than one person.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Since smoke is produced when air bag (inflator) module is deployed and pretensioner is activated, select well-ventilated area.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Air bag (inflator) module and seat belt pretensioner will immediately deploy &#x002F; activate when 12 volts vehicle battery is connected to it. Wear safety glasses throughout this entire deployment &#x002F; activation and disposal procedure.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Wear suitable ear protection when deploying air bag (inflator) module &#x002F; activating seat belt pretensioner. Also, advise those who are in area close to deployment &#x002F; activation site to wear suitable ear protection.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Do not deploy &#x002F; activate two or more air bag system components (air bag (inflator) modules and seat belt pretensioners) at the same time.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Never connect deployment harness to any 12 volts vehicle battery before connecting deployment harness to air bag (inflator) module and seat belt pretensioner. Deployment harness shall remain shorted and not be connected to 12 volts vehicle battery till you are ready to deploy air bag (inflator) module or activate seat belt pretensioner.
</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
</attention1>
<servinfosub id = "S6JB0B8206017001">
<title>
Deployment &#x002F; Activation Outside of Vehicle
</title>
<ptxt>
When you intend to return the vehicle to service, deploy the air bag (inflator) module(s) or activate seat belt pretensioner(s) outside of the vehicle.
</ptxt>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Turn ignition switch to LOCK position and remove key.
</ptxt>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Wear safety glasses during this deployment &#x002F; activation procedure.
</ptxt>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Check that there is no open, short or damage in special tools (deployment harness (A) and adapter cable (B)). If any faulty is found, do not use it and be sure to use new special tool.
</ptxt>
<servicetool>
<servicetoolitem id = "L8B0186">
<s-part>
(A)
</s-part>
<s-number num = "09932-75031">
09932&#8211;75031
</s-number>
<ptxt>
</ptxt>
</servicetoolitem>
<servicetoolitem id = "L8B0187">
<s-part>
(B)
</s-part>
<s-number num = "09932-76510">
09932&#8211;76510
</s-number>
</servicetoolitem>
</servicetool>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Short two deployment harness leads (1) together by fully seating one banana plug into the other.
</ptxt>
<attention1>
<ptxt>
Deployment harness (A) shall remain shorted and not be connected to 12 volts vehicle battery till you are ready to deploy air bag module or activate seat belt pretensioner.
</ptxt>
</attention1>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname = "I4RS0A820084.swf" width = "88.000mm" height = "61.499mm" ver = "01" gw = "204" gh = "157"/>
</figure>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Remove air bag (inflator) module(s) or seat belt pretensioner(s) from vehicle referring to 
<intxref refid = "S6JB0B8206005">Driver Air Bag (Inflator) Module Removal and Installation</intxref>
, 
<intxref refid = "S6JB0B8206007">Passenger Air Bag (Inflator) Module Removal and Installation</intxref>
, 
<intxref refid = "S6JB0B8206009">Side-Air Bag (Inflator) Module Removal and Installation</intxref>
, 
<intxref refid = "S6JB0B8206011">Side Curtain-Air Bag (Inflator) Module Removal and Installation</intxref>
 or 
<intxref refid = "S6JB0B8106002">Front Seat Belt Removal and Installation</intxref>
.
</ptxt>
<attention1>
<list1 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
For handing and storage of live air bag (inflator) module, select place where ambient temperature below 65 &#176;C (150 &#176;F), without high humidity and away from electric noise.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Always carry live air bag (inflator) module with trim cover away from you.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
When storing live air bag (inflator) module or when leaving live air bag (inflator) module unattended on bench or other surface, always face trim cover up and away from surface. It is also prohibited to place anything on top of the trim cover and stack air bag (inflator) modules. This is necessary so that free space is provided to allow air bag (inflator) module to expand in the unlikely event of accidental deployment.
</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
<ptxt>
Failure to follow procedures may result in personal injury.
</ptxt>
</attention1>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname = "I5JB0A820098.swf" width = "88.000mm" height = "104.425mm" ver = "02" gw = "229" gh = "279"/>
<callout>
<table frame = "all" colsep = "1" rowsep = "1">
<tgroup cols = "2" colsep = "1" rowsep = "1">
<colspec colnum = "1" colname = "1" colwidth = "0.236in"/>
<colspec colnum = "2" colname = "2" colwidth = "3.228in"/>
<tbody>
<row rowsep = "1">
<entry colname = "1" border-top = "1" border-bottom = "1" border-left = "1" border-right = "0" align = "right">
<ptxt>
&#x005B;A&#x005D;:
</ptxt>
</entry>
<entry colname = "2" border-top = "1" border-bottom = "1" border-left = "0" border-right = "1">
<ptxt>
Always carry air bag (inflator) module with trim cover (air bag opening) away from body.
</ptxt>
</entry>
</row>
<row rowsep = "0">
<entry colname = "1" border-top = "1" border-bottom = "1" border-left = "1" border-right = "0" align = "right">
<ptxt>
&#x005B;B&#x005D;:
</ptxt>
</entry>
<entry colname = "2" border-top = "1" border-bottom = "1" border-left = "0" border-right = "1">
<ptxt>
Always place air bag (inflator) module on workbench with trim cover (air bag opening) up, away from loose objects.
</ptxt>
</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</callout>
</figure>
<attention1>
<list1 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
For handling and storage of seat belt pretensioner, select place where ambient temperature is below 65 &#176;C (150 &#176;F), without high humidity and away from electric noise.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Never carry seat belt pretensioner by webbing.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
When placing seat belt pretensioner on workbench or other surface, be sure to lay it with its exhaust hole (1) side facing up. It is also prohibited to put something on seat belt pretensioner.
</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
<ptxt>
Otherwise, personal injury may result.
</ptxt>
</attention1>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname = "I4JA01822118.swf" width = "88.000mm" height = "44.100mm" ver = "01" gw = "164" gh = "108"/>
</figure>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Set air bag (inflator) module or seat belt pretensioner as follows.
</ptxt>
<list1 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
For driver air bag (inflator) module
</ptxt>
</item>
<list2 type = "ordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
Clear space (3) on ground about 185 cm (6 ft) in diameter where driver air bag (inflator) module (1) is set for deployment. Paved, outdoor location where there is no activity is preferred. If outdoor location is not available, use space on shop floor where there is no activity and sufficient ventilation is provided. Ensure no loose or flammable object exists within deployment area.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Place driver air bag (inflator) module (1) with its vinyl trim cover facing up (2) on ground in step a.
</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname = "I3JA01820036.swf" width = "88.000mm" height = "61.584mm" ver = "01" gw = "170" gh = "158"/>
</figure>
</item>
</list2>
</list1>
<list1 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
For passenger air bag (inflator) module
</ptxt>
</item>
<list2 type = "ordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
Clear space (3) on ground about 185 cm (6 ft) in diameter where passenger air bag (inflator) module (1) is set for deployment. Paved, outdoor location where there is no activity is preferred. If outdoor location is not available, use space on shop floor where there is no activity and sufficient ventilation is provided. Ensure no loose or flammable object exists within deployment area.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Place deployment fixture (A) on ground in step a.
</ptxt>
<servicetool>
<servicetoolitem id = "L8B0188">
<s-part>
(A)
</s-part>
<s-number num = "09932-75041">
09932&#8211;75041
</s-number>
<ptxt>
</ptxt>
</servicetoolitem>
</servicetool>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Fill plastic reservoir in deployment fixture (A) with water or sand. This is necessary to provide sufficient stabilization of fixture during deployment.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Attach passenger air bag (inflator) module (1) in deployment fixture (A) securely using M8 bolt (2).
</ptxt>
<attention2>
<ptxt>
Be sure to use M8 size and 7T strength bolt for fixing passenger air bag (inflator) module (1) to deployment fixture (A).
</ptxt>
</attention2>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname = "I5JB0A820099.swf" width = "88.000mm" height = "62.797mm" ver = "01" gw = "175" gh = "161"/>
</figure>
</item>
</list2>
</list1>
<list1 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
For side-air bag (inflator) module
</ptxt>
</item>
<list2 type = "ordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
Remove sleeve (1) and sleeve lock nut (2), if equipped.
</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname = "I4RS0A820088.swf" width = "88.000mm" height = "41.631mm" ver = "01" gw = "165" gh = "101"/>
</figure>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Clear space (3) on ground about 185 cm (6 ft) in diameter where side-air bag (inflator) module for deployment. Paved, outdoor location where there is no activity is preferred. If outdoor location is not available, space on shop floor where there is no activity and provide sufficient ventilation. Ensure no loose or flammable objects are within deployment area.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Place deployment fixture (A) on ground.
</ptxt>
<servicetool>
<servicetoolitem id = "L8B0189">
<s-part>
(A)
</s-part>
<s-number num = "09932-75041">
09932&#8211;75041
</s-number>
</servicetoolitem>
</servicetool>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Fill plastic reservoir in deployment fixture (A) with water or sand. This is necessary to provide sufficient stabilization of fixture during deployment.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Attach side-air bag (inflator) module (1) in deployment fixture using mounting attachment, sleeve lock nut and washer (2).
</ptxt>
<attention3>
<ptxt>
Make sure that deploying direction faces as shown in figure against mounting attachment.
</ptxt>
</attention3>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname = "I4RS0A820089.swf" width = "88.000mm" height = "63.150mm" ver = "01" gw = "161" gh = "162"/>
</figure>
</item>
</list2>
</list1>
<list1 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
For side curtain-air bag (inflator) module
</ptxt>
</item>
<list2 type = "ordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
Loosen nut (1) and remove bag (2) of side curtain-air bag (inflator) module.
</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname = "I5JB0A820100.swf" width = "88.000mm" height = "51.508mm" ver = "01" gw = "160" gh = "129"/>
</figure>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Tie side curtain-air bag inflator (1) to tire (3) with wire harness (2) as shown.
</ptxt>
<spec>
<title>
Wire harness specifications
</title>
<ptxt>
Stripped wire harness section 1.25 mm&#x00B2; (0.0019 in.&#x00B2;) or more (Stripped wire harness diameter 1.25 mm (0.05 in.) or more)
</ptxt>
</spec>
<attention2>
<ptxt>
Make sure that wire harness is tight. It is very dangerous if looseness in wire harness results in side curtain-air bag inflator flying off due to shock from inflator deploying.
</ptxt>
</attention2>
<attention3>
<ptxt>
Wind wire harness (2) around at least 3 times.
</ptxt>
</attention3>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Clear space (5) on ground about 185 cm (6 ft) in diameter where side curtain-air bag (inflator) module (1) is set for deployment. Paved, outdoor location where there is no activity is preferred. If outdoor location is not available, use space on shop floor where there is no activity and sufficient ventilation is provided. Ensure no loose or flammable object exists within activation area.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Pile tire with side curtain-air bag (inflator) module on tire (4).
</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname = "I5JB0A820101.swf" width = "88.000mm" height = "62.445mm" ver = "01" gw = "157" gh = "160"/>
</figure>
</item>
</list2>
</list1>
<list1 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
For seat belt pretensioner
</ptxt>
</item>
<list2 type = "ordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
Cut webbing (1) at tongue plate stopper (3) of seat belt pretensioner (2) side as shown.
</ptxt>
<attention3>
<ptxt>
Hold seat belt pretensioner (2) vertically in the same condition as it is installed. Otherwise, webbing can&#8217;t be pulled out.
</ptxt>
</attention3>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Remove tongue plate (4) and shoulder anchor (5) from webbing.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Tie webbing (1) tightly at 10 cm (3.9 in.) from cutting edge as shown.
</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname = "I3JA01820037.swf" width = "88.000mm" height = "48.686mm" ver = "01" gw = "186" gh = "121"/>
</figure>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname = "I4RS0A820104.swf" width = "88.000mm" height = "37.044mm" ver = "01" gw = "130" gh = "88"/>
</figure>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Tie seat belt pretensioner (2) with wire harness (3) to wheel-installed tire (4) as shown.
</ptxt>
<spec>
<title>
Wire harness specifications
</title>
<ptxt>
Stripped wire harness section 1.25 mm&#x00B2; (0.0019 in.&#x00B2;) or more (Stripped wire harness diameter 1.25 mm (0.05 in.) or more)
</ptxt>
</spec>
<attention3>
<ptxt>
Wind wire harness (3) around at least 3 times.
</ptxt>
</attention3>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Clear space (5) on ground about 185 cm (6 ft) in diameter where seat belt pretensioner (2) is to be activated. Paved, outdoor location where there is no activity is preferred. If outdoor location is not available, use space on shop floor where there is no activity and sufficient ventilation is provided. Ensure no loose or flammable object exists within activation area.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Place wheel-installed tire (4) with seat belt pretensioner (2) on ground in step e.
</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname = "I4RS0A820105.swf" width = "88.000mm" height = "63.150mm" ver = "01" gw = "146" gh = "162"/>
<callout>
<table frame = "all" colsep = "1" rowsep = "1">
<tgroup cols = "2" colsep = "1" rowsep = "1">
<colspec colnum = "1" colname = "1" colwidth = "0.315in"/>
<colspec colnum = "2" colname = "2" colwidth = "1.181in"/>
<tbody>
<row rowsep = "0">
<entry colname = "1" border-top = "1" border-bottom = "1" border-left = "1" border-right = "0" align = "right">
<ptxt>
1.
</ptxt>
</entry>
<entry colname = "2" border-top = "1" border-bottom = "1" border-left = "0" border-right = "1">
<ptxt>
Webbing
</ptxt>
</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</callout>
</figure>
</item>
</list2>
</list1>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Stretch deployment harness (A) from air bag (inflator) module or seat belt pretensioner to its full length 10 m (33 ft).
</ptxt>
<servicetool>
<servicetoolitem id = "L8B0190">
<s-part>
(A)
</s-part>
<s-number num = "09932-75031">
09932&#8211;75031
</s-number>
<ptxt>
</ptxt>
</servicetoolitem>
</servicetool>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Place 12 volts vehicle battery (1) near the shorted end of deployment harness (A).
</ptxt>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Check that area around air bag (inflator) module or seat belt pretensioner is clear of all people and loose or flammable objects.
</ptxt>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Connect adapter cable (B) as follows.
</ptxt>
<servicetool>
<servicetoolitem id = "L8B0191">
<s-part>
(B)
</s-part>
<s-number num = "09932-76510">
09932&#8211;76510
</s-number>
</servicetoolitem>
</servicetool>
<list1 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
For driver air bag (inflator) module &#x005B;A&#x005D;
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
Check that driver air bag (inflator) module is placed with its vinyl trim cover facing up, and connect adapter cable (B) to driver air bag (inflator) module.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
For passenger air bag (inflator) module &#x005B;B&#x005D;
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
Check that passenger air bag (inflator) module is firmly and properly secured on deployment fixture (special tool), and connect adapter cable (B) to passenger air bag (inflator) module.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
For side-air bag (inflator) module &#x005B;C&#x005D;
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
Verify that side-air bag (inflator) module is firmly and properly on deployment fixture (special tool), and connect adapter cable (B) to side-air bag (inflator) module.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
For side curtain-air bag (inflator) module &#x005B;D&#x005D;
</ptxt>
</item>
<list2 type = "ordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
Connect adapter cable (B) to side curtain-air bag (inflator) module.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Pile 2 tires (2) and wheel-installed tire (3) on top of tire with side curtain-air bag (inflator) (4), and tie them with wire harness (5) as shown.
</ptxt>
<spec>
<title>
Wire harness specifications
</title>
<ptxt>
Stripped wire harness section 1.25 mm&#x00B2; (0.0019 in.&#x00B2;) or more (Stripped wire harness diameter 1.25 mm (0.05 in.) or more)
</ptxt>
</spec>
<attention3>
<ptxt>
Wind wire harness (5) around at least 2 times.
</ptxt>
</attention3>
</item>
</list2>
</list1>
<list1 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
For seat belt pretensioner &#x005B;E&#x005D;
</ptxt>
</item>
<list2 type = "ordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
Connect adapter cable (B) to seat belt pretensioner.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Pile 2 wheel-installed tires (3) on top of tire with seat belt pretensioner (6), and tie them with wire harness (5) as shown.
</ptxt>
<spec>
<title>
Wire harness specifications
</title>
<ptxt>
Stripped wire harness section 1.25 mm&#x00B2; (0.0019 in.&#x00B2;) or more (Stripped wire harness diameter 1.25 mm (0.05 in.) or more)
</ptxt>
</spec>
<attention3>
<ptxt>
Wind wire harness (5) around at least 2 times.
</ptxt>
</attention3>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Drape blanket (7) over those tires.
</ptxt>
</item>
</list2>
</list1>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Connect adapter cable (B) to deployment harness (A) connector and lock connectors with lock lever.
</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname = "I5JB0A820102.swf" width = "88.000mm" height = "241.656mm" ver = "01" gw = "140" gh = "668"/>
</figure>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Notify all people in immediate area that you intend to deploy &#x002F; activate air bag (inflator) module or seat belt pretensioner.
</ptxt>
<attention3>
<list1 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
When air bag (inflator) module deploys and seat belt pretensioner activates, rapid gas expansion will create substantial report. Wear suitable ear protection. Notify all people in immediate area that you intend to deploy air bag (inflator) module or activate seat belt pretensioner and suitable ear protection should be worn.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
When driver air bag (inflator) module deploys, driver air bag (inflator) module may jump about 30 cm (1 ft) vertically. This is normal reaction to force of rapid gas expansion inside of drive air bag (inflator) module.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
After air bag (inflator) module has been deployed, surface of air bag (inflator) may contain powdery residue. This powder consists primarily of cornstarch (used to lubricate bag (inflator) as it inflates) and by products of chemical reaction.
</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
</attention3>
<attention1>
<list1 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
Do not place deployed air bag (inflator) module and activated seat belt pretensioner near any flammable objects.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Do not apply water, oil, etc. to deployed air bag (inflator) module and activated seat belt pretensioner.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Wait for about 30 minutes before touching any metal surface of air bag (inflater) module or seat belt pretensioner module. Disregarding these precautions may cause fire or personal injury.
</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
<ptxt>
Failure to follow procedures may result in fire or personal injury.
</ptxt>
</attention1>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Separate two banana plugs (1) on deployment harness.
</ptxt>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Connect deployment harness to 12 volts vehicle battery (2). This will immediately deploy or activate air bag (inflator) module or seat belt pretensioner.
</ptxt>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Disconnect deployment harness from 12 volts vehicle battery (2) and short two deployment harness leads together by fully seating one banana plug into the other.
</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname = "I2RH01820069.swf" width = "88.000mm" height = "43.084mm" ver = "01" gw = "170" gh = "105"/>
</figure>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
In the unlikely event that air bag (inflator) module or seat belt pretensioner did not deploy &#x002F; activate after following these procedures, proceed immediately with Step 22) through 25). If air bag (inflator) module or seat belt pretensioner did deploy or activate, proceed with Steps 18) through 21).
</ptxt>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Put on pair of shop gloves to protect your hands from possible irritation and heat when handling deployed air bag (inflator) module or activated seat belt pretensioner.
</ptxt>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Disconnect adapter cable (special tool) from air bag (inflator) module or seat belt pretensioner as soon as possible. This will prevent adapter cable (special tool) from damage due to possible contact with hot air bag (inflator) module or hot seat belt pretensioner.
</ptxt>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Check adapter cable as follows.
</ptxt>
<list1 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
For air bag (inflator) module
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
Be sure to check air bag (inflator) module adapter cable (special tool) for damage after deployment and replace it with new adapter cable (special tool), if it is damaged.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
For seat belt pretensioner
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
Be sure to check seat belt pretensioner adapter cable (special tool) for damage after seat belt pretensioner is activated. Replace it with spare connector (special tool) or new adapter, if necessary.
</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Dispose of deployed air bag (inflator) module (1) or activated seat belt pretensioner (2) through normal refuse channels after it has cooled for at least 30 minutes and tightly seal air bag (inflator) module (1) or seat belt pretensioner (2) in strong vinyl bag. Refer to 
<intxref refid = "S6JB0B8206018">Deployed Air Bag (Inflator) Module and Activated Seat Belt Pretensioner Disposal</intxref>
 for details.
</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname = "I3JA01820116.swf" width = "88.000mm" height = "48.884mm" ver = "01" gw = "177" gh = "122"/>
</figure>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Wash your hands with mild soap and water afterward.
</ptxt>
<attention3>
<ptxt>
Remaining steps are to be followed in the unlikely event that air bag (inflator) module did not deploy or seat belt pretensioner did not activate.
</ptxt>
</attention3>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Ensure that deployment harness has been disconnected from 12 volts vehicle battery and that its two banana plugs have been shorted together by fully seating one banana plug into the other.
</ptxt>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Disconnect deployment harness and adapter cable from air bag (inflator) module or seat belt pretensioner.
</ptxt>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Temporarily store undeployed air bag (inflator) module referring to 
<intxref refid = "S6JB0B8200001">Precautions on Service and Diagnosis of Air Bag System</intxref>
 for details.
</ptxt>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Contact your local distributor for further assistance.
</ptxt>
</s1>
</servinfosub>
<servinfosub id = "S6JB0B8206017002">
<title>
Deployment &#x002F; Activation Inside of Vehicle
</title>
<ptxt>
When the vehicle will be destroyed, or salvaged for component parts, deploy the air bag modules and&#x002F;or activate seat belt pretensioners installed on vehicle.
</ptxt>
<attention3>
<ptxt>
If equipped with the seat belt pretensioners, activate both side of seat belt pretensioners at the same time when using special tool (C).
</ptxt>
</attention3>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Turn ignition switch to LOCK position, remove key and put on safety glasses.
</ptxt>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Remove all loose objects from front seats and instrument panel.
</ptxt>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Disconnect air bag (inflator) module or seat belt pretensioner connector as follows.
</ptxt>
<list1 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
For driver air bag (inflator) module &#x005B;A&#x005D;:
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
Disconnect contact coil connector (1) located near base of steering column.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
For passenger air bag (inflator) module &#x005B;D&#x005D;:
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
Remove glove box from instrument panel and disconnect passenger air bag (inflator) module connector (2).
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
For side-air bag (inflator) module &#x005B;E&#x005D;
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
Disconnect side-air bag (inflator) module connectors (3) under front seat cushion.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
For side curtain-air bag (inflator) module &#x005B;F&#x005D;
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
Remove rear pillar trim and disconnect side curtain-air bag (inflator) module connectors (4).
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
For seat belt pretensioners (right and left) &#x005B;G&#x005D;
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
Remove both side (driver and passenger side) center pillar lower trim and disconnect seat belt pretensioner connectors (5).
</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Confirm that each air bag (inflator) module and&#x002F;or seat belt pretensioners is securely mounted.
</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname = "I5JB0A820103.swf" width = "88.000mm" height = "217.314mm" ver = "01" gw = "230" gh = "599"/>
<callout>
<table frame = "all" colsep = "1" rowsep = "1">
<tgroup cols = "2" colsep = "1" rowsep = "1">
<colspec colnum = "1" colname = "1" colwidth = "0.315in"/>
<colspec colnum = "2" colname = "2" colwidth = "1.968in"/>
<tbody>
<row rowsep = "1">
<entry colname = "1" border-top = "1" border-bottom = "1" border-left = "1" border-right = "0" align = "right">
<ptxt>
&#x005B;B&#x005D;:
</ptxt>
</entry>
<entry colname = "2" border-top = "1" border-bottom = "1" border-left = "0" border-right = "1" align = "left">
<ptxt>
For vehicle without cruise control system
</ptxt>
</entry>
</row>
<row rowsep = "0">
<entry colname = "1" border-top = "1" border-bottom = "1" border-left = "1" border-right = "0" align = "right">
<ptxt>
&#x005B;C&#x005D;:
</ptxt>
</entry>
<entry colname = "2" border-top = "1" border-bottom = "1" border-left = "0" border-right = "1" align = "left">
<ptxt>
For vehicle with cruise control system
</ptxt>
</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</callout>
</figure>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Check that there is no open, short or damage in special tools (deployment harness (A), adapter cable (B), (C) and (D)). If any faulty condition is found, do not use it and be sure to use new special tool. And connect adapter cable (B), (C) or (D) to deployment harness (A) and lock connectors with lock slider.
</ptxt>
<servicetool>
<servicetoolitem id = "L8B0192">
<s-part>
(A)
</s-part>
<s-number num = "09932-75031">
09932&#8211;75031
</s-number>
<ptxt>
</ptxt>
</servicetoolitem>
<servicetoolitem id = "L8B0193">
<s-part>
(B)
</s-part>
<s-number num = "09932-78332">
09932&#8211;78332
</s-number>
</servicetoolitem>
<servicetoolitem id = "L8B0194">
<s-part>
(C)
</s-part>
<s-number num = "09932-77310">
09932&#8211;77310
</s-number>
</servicetoolitem>
<servicetoolitem id = "L8B0195">
<s-part>
(D)
</s-part>
<s-number num = "09932-76510">
09932&#8211;76510
</s-number>
</servicetoolitem>
</servicetool>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Short two deployment harness leads together by fully seating one banana plug (1) into the other.
</ptxt>
<attention1>
<ptxt>
Deployment harness (A) shall remain shorted and not be connected to 12 volts vehicle battery until you are ready to deploy air bag (inflator) module or activate seat belt pretensioner.
</ptxt>
</attention1>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Connect adapter cable (B), (C) or (D) in series with deployment harness (A) to air bag (inflator) module or seat belt pretensioner as follows.
</ptxt>
<list1 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
For driver air bag (inflator) module &#x005B;A&#x005D;
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
Connect adapter cable (B) (For vehicle without cruise control system &#x005B;B&#x005D;) or (C) (For vehicle with cruise control system &#x005B;C&#x005D;) in series with deployment harness (A) and push adapter cable (B) or (C) connector to driver air bag (inflator) module connector till click can be heard.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
For passenger air bag (inflator) module &#x005B;D&#x005D;
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
Connect adapter cable (C) in series with deployment harness (A) and push adapter cable (C) connector to passenger air bag (inflator) module connector till click can be heard.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
For side-air bag (inflator) module &#x005B;E&#x005D;
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
Connect adapter cable (B) in series with deployment harness (A) and push adapter cable (C) connector to side bag (inflator) module connector till click can be heard.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
For side curtain-air bag (inflator) module &#x005B;F&#x005D;
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
Connect adapter cable (D) in series with deployment harness (A) to curtain bag (inflator) module and lock connector with lock part.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
For seat belt pretensioners &#x005B;G&#x005D;
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
Connect adapter cable (D) in series with deployment harness (A) to seat belt pretensioner and lock connector with lock part.
</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname = "I5JB0A820104.swf" width = "88.000mm" height = "236.717mm" ver = "01" gw = "227" gh = "654"/>
</figure>
</item>
</list1>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Route deployment harness (1) out of vehicle.
</ptxt>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Check that inside of vehicle and area surrounding vehicle are clear of all people and loose or flammable objects.
</ptxt>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Stretch deployment harness (1) to its full length 10 m (33 ft).
</ptxt>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Place 12 volts vehicle battery (2) near shorted end of deployment harness (1).
</ptxt>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Completely cover windshield area and front door window openings with drop cloth, a blanket or any similar item. This reduces possibility of injury due to possible fragmentation of vehicle&#8217;s glass or interior.
</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname = "I5JB0A820105.swf" width = "88.000mm" height = "58.211mm" ver = "01" gw = "228" gh = "148"/>
</figure>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Notify all people in immediate area that you intend to deploy air bag (inflator) module or activate seat belt pretensioners.
</ptxt>
<attention3>
<list1 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
When air bag (inflator) module deploys or seat belt pretensioners activate, rapid gas expansion will create substantial report. Wear suitable ear protection. Notify all people in immediate area that you intend to deploy air bag (inflator) module or to activate seat belt pretensioner and suitable ear protection should be worn.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
After air bag (inflator) module has been deployed, surface of air bag may contain powdery residue. This powder consists primarily of cornstarch (used to lubricate air bag (inflator) module as it inflates) and by-products of chemical reaction.
</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
</attention3>
<attention1>
<list1 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
Do not place deployed air bag (inflator) module and activated seat belt pretensioners near any flammable objects.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Do not apply water, oil, etc. to deployed air bag (inflator) module and activated seat belt pretensioners.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Wait for about 30 minutes before touching any metal surface of air bag (inflater) module or seat belt pretensioner modules. Disregarding these precautions may cause fire or personal injury.
</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
<ptxt>
Failure to follow procedures may result in fire or personal injury.
</ptxt>
</attention1>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Separate two banana plugs (1) on deployment harness (2).
</ptxt>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Connect deployment harness (2) to 12 volts vehicle battery (3). This will immediately deploy or activate air bag (inflator) module or seat belt pretensioners.
</ptxt>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Disconnect deployment harness (2) from 12 volts vehicle battery (3) and short two deployment harness leads together by fully seating one banana plug into the other.
</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname = "I5JB0A820106.swf" width = "88.000mm" height = "62.445mm" ver = "01" gw = "225" gh = "160"/>
</figure>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Repeat Steps 3) through 16) to deploy &#x002F; activate air bag (inflator) modules and seat belt pretensioners which has not been deployed &#x002F; activated, if any.
</ptxt>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
In the unlikely event that air bag (inflator) module and seat belt pretensioners after following these procedures, proceed immediately with Step 24) through 26). If air bag (inflator) module and seat belt pretensioners did deploy &#x002F; activate, proceed with Steps 19) through 23).
</ptxt>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Carefully remove drop cloth from vehicle and clean off any fragments or discard it entirely.
</ptxt>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Put on pair of shop gloves to protect your hands from possible irritation and heat when handling deployed air bag (inflator) module and activated seat belt pretensioners.
</ptxt>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Disconnect adapter cable (special tool) from air bag (inflator) module or seat belt pretensioner as soon as possible. This will prevent adapter cable (special tool) from damage due to possible contact with hot air bag (inflator) module or hot seat belt pretensioner.
</ptxt>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Check adapter cable connector as follows.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
Adapter cable connector (special tool) is designed to be reused. However it should be inspected for damage after deployment and replaced if necessary.
</ptxt>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
With air bag (inflator) modules deployed and seat belt pretensioners activated, vehicle may be scrapped in the same manner as non-air bag system &#x002F; seat belt pretensioner equipped vehicle.
</ptxt>
<attention3>
<ptxt>
Remaining steps are to be followed in the unlikely event that air bag (inflator) module did not deploy or seat belt pretensioner did not activate.
</ptxt>
</attention3>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Remove undeployed air bag (inflator) module(s) and&#x002F;or inactivated seat belt pretensioner(s) from vehicle. For driver air bag (inflator) module, refer to 
<intxref refid = "S6JB0B8206005">Driver Air Bag (Inflator) Module Removal and Installation</intxref>
. For passenger air bag (inflator) module, refer to 
<intxref refid = "S6JB0B8206007">Passenger Air Bag (Inflator) Module Removal and Installation</intxref>
. For side air bag (inflator) module, refer to 
<intxref refid = "S6JB0B8206009">Side-Air Bag (Inflator) Module Removal and Installation</intxref>
. For side curtain-air bag (inflator) module, 
<intxref refid = "S6JB0B8206011">Side Curtain-Air Bag (Inflator) Module Removal and Installation</intxref>
. For seat belt pretensioner, refer to 
<intxref refid = "S6JB0B8106002">Front Seat Belt Removal and Installation</intxref>
.
</ptxt>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Temporarily store undeployed air bag (inflator) module referring to 
<intxref refid = "S6JB0B8200001">Precautions on Service and Diagnosis of Air Bag System</intxref>
 for details.
</ptxt>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Contact your local distributor for further assistance.
</ptxt>
</s1>
</servinfosub>
</servinfo>
</servinfotype>
</configtype>
</servcat>
</section></manual></suzuki>
