<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="..\config\suzuki.xsl" ?><!DOCTYPE suzuki [<!ENTITY % sdatacharaents SYSTEM "..\config\sdatacharaents.txt">%sdatacharaents;]><suzuki><manual>
<section sectnbr = "1G">
<servcat sctnbr = "01" scnbr = "07">
<configtype typenbr = "0">
<servinfotype sitcode = "0">
<servinfo servinfosgmlid = "S5JB0B1700001" svcinfotypenbr = "01" svcinfoqualnbr = "01" supplyoff = "1" modify = "0">
<title>
Precautions on Fuel System Service
</title>
<attention1>
<list1 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
Before attempting service of any type on fuel system, the following should be always observed in order to reduce the risk of fire and personal injury.
</ptxt>
</item>
<list2 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
Disconnect negative (&#8211;) cable at battery.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Do not smoke, and place no smoking signs near work area.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Be sure to have CO2 fire extinguisher handy.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Be sure to perform work in a well-ventilated area and away from any open flames (such as gas hot heater).
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Wear safety glasses.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
To relieve fuel vapor pressure in fuel tank, remove fuel filler cap from fuel filler neck and then reinstall it.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
As fuel feed line is still under high fuel pressure even after engine was stopped, loosening or disconnecting fuel feed line directly may cause dangerous spout of fuel to occur where loosened or disconnected. Before loosening or disconnecting fuel high presser line, make sure to relieve fuel pressure referring to 
<intxref refid = "S5JB0B1706002">Fuel Pressure Relief Procedure</intxref>
.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
A small amount of fuel may be released after the fuel line is disconnected. In order to reduce the chance of personal injury, cover the fitting to be disconnected with a lint-free cloth. Be sure to put that cloth in an approved container when disconnection is completed.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
When connecting fuel pipe flare nut, first tighten flare nut by hand and then tighten it to specified torque.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
The system can inject the diesel fuel into the engine at a pressure up to 160,000 kPa (1,600 kg&#x002F;cm&#x00B2;, 22,760 psi). Before carrying out any work, check that the injector rail is not under pressure and that the fuel temperature is not too high.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Do not place your hand near to a leak on the high pressure fuel circuit.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Do not run engine with disconnecting fuel pipe and&#x002F;or removing fuel system components.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Do not expose removed fuel system parts to dust. Keep always clean.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
When servicing the fuel tank, it should be treated with respect, with no contact with sharp edges or hot surfaces. In addition, the fuel tank should not be dropped since fuel tank, fuel pump and other components can be damaged by the impact. If dropped, all components should be replaced because there is a risk of damage.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Note that fuel hose connection varies with each type of pipe. Be sure to connect and clamp each hose correctly referring to 
<intxref refid = "S5JB0B1706038">Fuel Hose Disconnecting and Reconnecting</intxref>
.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
After connecting, mark sure that it has no twist or kink.
</ptxt>
</item>
</list2>
<item>
<ptxt>
Fuel vapor is hazardous. It can very easily ignite, causing serious injury and damage. Always keep sparks and flames away from fuel. Fuel line spills and leaks are dangerous. Fuel can ignite and cause serious injuries or death and damage.
</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
</attention1>
<p-change/>
<list1 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
The fuel system must be checked for leaks after service work referring to 
<intxref refid = "S5JB0B1706003">Fuel Leakage Check Procedure</intxref>
.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
The fuel system is very sensitive to contamination. The risks caused by the introduction of contamination are:
</ptxt>
</item>
<list2 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
damage or destruction of the high pressure injection system and the engine.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
seizing or leaking of a component.
</ptxt>
</item>
</list2>
<item>
<ptxt>
When servicing on the high pressure direct injection system, must be performed under very clean conditions.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
This means that no impurities (particles a few microns in side) get into the system during dismantling or into the circuits via the fuel unions.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
The cleanliness principle must be applied from the fuel filter to the injectors.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Contamination is caused by:
</ptxt>
</item>
<list2 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
metal or plastic chips,
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
paint,
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
fibres: boxes, brushes, paper, clothing, cloths,
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
foreign bodies such as hair,
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
ambient air,
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
etc.
</ptxt>
</item>
</list2>
<item>
<ptxt>
It is not possible to clean the engine using a high pressure washer because of the risk of damaging connections.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
In addition, moisture may collect in the connectors and create electrical connection problems.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
The technician should wear clean overalls.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Ensure that you have the plug caps (1) for the unions to be opened. Plug caps are to be used once only. After use, they must be thrown away (once used they are soiled and cleaning is not sufficient to make them reusable).
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
Unused plug caps must be thrown away, also.
</ptxt>
<attention3>
<list1 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
Plug cap set is available as a spare part.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Plug unions as soon as possible when removing &#x002F; disconnecting fuel system component in order to prevent dust from invading.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
Similarly, do not remove plug cap immediately before when installing &#x002F; connecting fuel system component.
</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
</attention3>
<p-change/>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname = "I5JB0B170045.swf" width = "183.000mm" height = "161.575mm" ver = "02" gw = "464" gh = "441"/>
<callout>
<table frame = "all" colsep = "1" rowsep = "1">
<tgroup cols = "4" colsep = "1" rowsep = "1">
<colspec colnum = "1" colname = "1" colwidth = "0.315in"/>
<colspec colnum = "2" colname = "2" colwidth = "0.819in"/>
<colspec colnum = "3" colname = "3" colwidth = "0.315in"/>
<colspec colnum = "4" colname = "4" colwidth = "1.007in"/>
<tbody>
<row rowsep = "0">
<entry colname = "1" border-top = "1" border-bottom = "1" border-left = "1" border-right = "0" valign = "top" align = "right">
<ptxt>
1.
</ptxt>
</entry>
<entry colname = "2" border-top = "1" border-bottom = "1" border-left = "0" border-right = "1" valign = "top" align = "left">
<ptxt>
Plug cap
</ptxt>
</entry>
<entry colname = "3" border-top = "1" border-bottom = "1" border-left = "1" border-right = "0" valign = "top" align = "right">
<ptxt>
<symbol name = "MADONOT" width = "5.132mm" height = "3.048mm"/>
:
</ptxt>
</entry>
<entry colname = "4" border-top = "1" border-bottom = "1" border-left = "0" border-right = "1" valign = "top" align = "left">
<ptxt>
Do not reuse.
</ptxt>
</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</callout>
</figure>
</item>
<p-change/>
<item>
<ptxt>
Ensure that you have hermetically resalable plastic bags for storing removed parts. Stored parts will therefore be less subject to the risk of impurities. The bags must be used only once, and after use they must be thrown away.
</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname = "I4RH0A170052.swf" width = "183.000mm" height = "33.982mm" ver = "01" gw = "300" gh = "79"/>
</figure>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Make sure that lint-free towelettes. The use of a normal cloth or paper for cleaning purposes is forbidden.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
These are not lint-free and may contaminate the fuel circuit of the system. Each lint-free cloth should only be used once.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Carry out any servicing as much as possible with the plug cap installed in order to prevent impurities from entering the system.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Instructions to be followed before opening the fuel circuit.
</ptxt>
</item>
<list2 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
For each operation, use new thinner (used thinner contains impurities). Pour it into a clean receptacle.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
For each operation, use a clean brush which is in good condition (the brush must not shed its bristles).
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Use a brush and thinners to clean the connections to be opened.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Blow compressed air over the cleaned parts (tools, cleaned the same way as the parts, connections and injection system zone). Check that no bristles remain adhered.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Wash your hands before and during the operation if necessary.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
When wearing leather protective gloves, cover these with latex gloves.
</ptxt>
</item>
</list2>
<item>
<ptxt>
Instructions to be followed during the operation.
</ptxt>
</item>
<list2 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
As soon as the circuit is open, all openings must be plugged to prevent impurities from entering the system by using the plug cap. They must not, under any circumstances, be reused.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Close the hermetically sealed bag, even if it has to be reopened shortly afterwards.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
Ambient air carries contamination.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
All components of the injection system that are removed must be stored in a hermetically sealed plastic bag once the plugs have been inserted.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
The use of a brush, thinner, bellows, sponge or normal cloth is strictly forbidden once the circuit has been opened.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
These items are likely to allow impurities to enter the system.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
A new component replacing an old one must not be removed from its packaging until it is to be fitted to the vehicle.
</ptxt>
</item>
</list2>
</list1>
</servinfo>
</servinfotype>
</configtype>
</servcat>
</section></manual></suzuki>
