<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="..\config\suzuki.xsl" ?><!DOCTYPE suzuki [<!ENTITY % sdatacharaents SYSTEM "..\config\sdatacharaents.txt">%sdatacharaents;]><suzuki><manual>
<section sectnbr = "2B">
<servcat sctnbr = "02" scnbr = "02">
<configtype typenbr = "0">
<servinfotype sitcode = "1">
<servinfo servinfosgmlid = "S5JB0B2201002" svcinfotypenbr = "03" svcinfoqualnbr = "01" page = "2" supplyoff = "0" modify = "0">
<title>
Front Wheel Alignment Construction
</title>
<ptxt>
Among factors for front wheel alignment, only toe setting can be adjusted. Camber and caster are not adjustable. 
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
Therefore, should camber or caster be out of specification due to the damage caused by hazardous road conditions or collision, whether the damage is in body or in suspension should be determined and damaged body should be repaired or damaged suspension should be replaced.
</ptxt>
<servinfosub id = "S5JB0B2201002001">
<title>
Preliminary Checks Prior to Adjustment Front Wheel Alignment
</title>
<ptxt>
Steering and vibration complaints are not always the result of improper wheel alignment. An additional item to be checked is the possibility of tire lead due to worn or improperly manufactured tires. &#8220;Lead&#8221; is the vehicle deviation from a straight path on a level road without hand pressure on the steering wheel. Refer to 
<intxref refid = "S5JB0B2401006">Radial Tire Lead &#x002F; Pull Description</intxref>
 in order to determine if the vehicle has a tire lead problem. Before making any adjustment affecting wheel alignment, the following checks and inspections should be made to ensure correctness of alignment readings and alignment adjustments:
</ptxt>
<list1 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
Check all tires for proper inflation pressures and approximately the same tread wear.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Check for loose of ball joints. Check tie-rod ends; if excessive looseness is noted, it must be corrected before adjusting.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Check for run-out of wheels and tires.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Check vehicle trim heights; if it is out of limit and a correction is needed, it must be done before adjusting toe.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Check for loose of suspension control arms.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Check for loose or missing stabilizer bar attachments.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Consideration must be given to excess loads, such as tool boxes. If this excess load is normally carried in vehicle, it should remain in vehicle during alignment checks.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Consider condition of equipment being used to check alignment and follow manufacturer&#8217;s instructions.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Regardless of equipment used to check alignment, vehicle must be placed on a level surface.
</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
<attention3>
<ptxt>
To prevent possible incorrect reading of toe, camber or caster, vehicle front and rear end must be moved up and down a few times before inspection.
</ptxt>
</attention3>
</servinfosub>
</servinfo>
</servinfotype>
</configtype>
</servcat>
</section></manual></suzuki>
