<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="..\config\suzuki.xsl" ?><!DOCTYPE suzuki [<!ENTITY % sdatacharaents SYSTEM "..\config\sdatacharaents.txt">%sdatacharaents;]><suzuki><manual>
<section sectnbr = "1C">
<servcat sctnbr = "01" scnbr = "03">
<configtype typenbr = "0">
<servinfotype sitcode = "6">
<servinfo servinfosgmlid = "S5JB0B1306028" svcinfotypenbr = "08" svcinfoqualnbr = "03" page = "2" supplyoff = "1" modify = "0">
<title>
Diesel Particulate Filter After-sales Regeneration Procedure
</title>
<attention1>
<ptxt>
During after-sales regeneration, exhaust gas temperature rises significantly and excessive smoke and strong smell occur.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
In order to reduce risk of fire and personal injury, this work must be performed in outside of work shop or a well ventilated area with an exhaust gas extractor approved at 400 &#176;C (750 &#176;F) and nothing should be left in vicinity of exhaust system components.
</ptxt>
</attention1>
<attention2>
<list1 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
Check the engine oil level before performing this procedure to prevent the engine damage. Engine oil level should be between the Low and Full level marks on the gauge.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
It is essential to change engine oil after this procedure in order to avoid any damage to the engine.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Perform diesel particulate filter after-sales regeneration only at the following conditions.
</ptxt>
</item>
<list2 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
<intxref refid = "S5JB0B1104132">DTC P1431: Clogged Particulate Filter Failures Malfunction</intxref>
 is detected.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
<intxref refid = "S5JB0B1104133">DTC P1436: Regeneration Request Failures Malfunction</intxref>
 is detected.
</ptxt>
</item>
</list2>
</list1>
</attention2>
<attention3>
<ptxt>
For further detail of SUZUKI scan tool, refer to its operator&#8217;s manual.
</ptxt>
</attention3>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Check engine oil level referring to 
<intxref refid = "S5JB0B0206004">Engine Oil and Filter Change</intxref>
.
</ptxt>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Locate vehicle in outside of workshop or well ventilated area with connecting exhaust gas extractor to exhaust pipe.
</ptxt>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Connect SUZUKI scan tool to data link connector (DLC) with ignition switch OFF.
</ptxt>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Start engine.
</ptxt>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Select &#8220;Regeneration&#8221; under &#8220;Miscellaneous test&#8221; (&#8220;MISC. TEST&#8221;) of SUZUKI scan tool, and follow instructions displayed in SUZUKI scan tool.
</ptxt>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Proceed after-sales regeneration automatically as follows.
</ptxt>
<attention3>
<ptxt>
Ensure to perform each step of regeneration by observing carefully the engine speed and the engine sound at each step. Because this procedure does not finish automatically and SUZUKI scan tool does not indicate any status of this procedure and the result of regeneration.
</ptxt>
</attention3>
<s2>
<ptxt>
Phase 1: Warming up
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
The engine speed is raised to 1500 rpm for at least 3 minutes or until engine coolant temperature reaches 80 &#176;C (176 &#176;F)
</ptxt>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>
Phase 2: Regenerating
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
Injection timing is shifted to post injection (a change in the engine operation sound can be heard) and start regeneration.
</ptxt>
<attention3>
<ptxt>
Phase 2 lasts approximately 20 minutes.
</ptxt>
</attention3>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>
Phase 3: Cooling down
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
The injection is shifted to normal timing again.
</ptxt>
<attention2>
<ptxt>
To avoid thermal shock in the diesel particulate filter, do not stop engine at phase 3.
</ptxt>
</attention2>
</s2>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Confirm &#8220;Diesel PF inlet Temp&#8221; under &#8220;Data list&#8221; of SUZUKI scan tool, and wait until it decreases to 200 &#176;C (392 &#176;F) or less.
</ptxt>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Stop engine.
</ptxt>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Turn ignition switch to OFF position, and wait for 15 minutes or more.
</ptxt>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Clear DTC referring to 
<intxref refid = "S5JB0B1104006">DTC Clearance</intxref>
.
</ptxt>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
After engine is cooled, replace engine oil and oil filter referring to 
<intxref refid = "S5JB0B0206004">Engine Oil and Filter Change</intxref>
.
</ptxt>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Check as follows that aftersales-regeneration is correctly performed.
</ptxt>
<attention2>
<ptxt>
When driving, be sure to select in safe place where there is neither any traffic nor any traffic accident possibility and be very careful during driving to avoid occurrence of an accident.
</ptxt>
</attention2>
<s2>
<ptxt>
Drive vehicle in the following each condition in order to make ECU recognize actually soot mass after after-sales regeneration.
</ptxt>
<s3>
<ptxt>
At 80 km&#x002F;h for 10 minutes
</ptxt>
</s3>
<s3>
<ptxt>
At 40 km&#x002F;h for 5 minutes
</ptxt>
</s3>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>
Using SUZUKI scan tool, check that &#8220;Diesel PF soot mass&#8221; parameter is 8 g (0.28 oz) or less.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
If it is over 8g (0.28 oz), aftersales regeneration is not correctly performed.Proceed to next step.
</ptxt>
</s2>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
If aftersales regeneration is not correctly performed, check as follows.
</ptxt>
<attention2>
<ptxt>
Be sure to change engine oil after each after-sales regeneration.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
Otherwise, engine will be damaged due to degraded engine oil.
</ptxt>
</attention2>
<s2>
<ptxt>
Check that connection and&#x002F;or hose of differential pressure sensor.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
If faulty condition is found, repair or replace it.
</ptxt>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>
Restart aftersales-regeneration referring to 
<intxref refid = "S5JB0B1306028">Diesel Particulate Filter After-sales Regeneration Procedure</intxref>
 and check the following condition during this after-sales regeneration.
</ptxt>
<list1 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
Check exhaust system for leakage.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
If leakage is found, repair or replace faulty condition.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Using SUZUKI scan tool, check that the following parameters are over 550 &#176;C (1022 &#176;F).
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
If not, replace catalytic converter referring to 
<intxref refid = "S5JB0B1B06001">Exhaust System Components</intxref>
.
</ptxt>
</item>
<list2 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
Diesel PF in Temp
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Diesel PF out Temp
</ptxt>
</item>
</list2>
</list1>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>
After after-sales regeneration, check &#8220;Diesel PF soot mass&#8221; in the same manner as step 12).
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
If &#8220;Diesel PF soot mass&#8221; is over 8 g (0.28 oz) again, replace diesel particulate filter referring to 
<intxref refid = "S5JB0B1B06003">Diesel Particulate Filter Removal and Installation</intxref>
.
</ptxt>
</s2>
</s1>
</servinfo>
</servinfotype>
</configtype>
</servcat>
</section></manual></suzuki>
