<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="..\config\suzuki.xsl" ?><!DOCTYPE suzuki [<!ENTITY % sdatacharaents SYSTEM "..\config\sdatacharaents.txt">%sdatacharaents;]><suzuki><manual>
<section sectnbr = "8B">
<servcat sctnbr = "08" scnbr = "02">
<configtype typenbr = "0">
<servinfotype sitcode = "0">
<servinfo servinfosgmlid = "S5JB0B8200002" svcinfotypenbr = "01" svcinfoqualnbr = "01" page = "2" supplyoff = "0" modify = "0">
<title>
Precautions on Handling and Storage of Air Bag System Components
</title>
<servinfosub id = "S5JB0B8200002001">
<title>
SDM
</title>
<attention1>
<ptxt>
Never power up air bag system when SDM is not rigidly attached to the vehicle. Otherwise, personal injury may result.
</ptxt>
</attention1>
<attention2>
<ptxt>
After detecting one time of such collision as to meet deployment conditions, SDM must not be used. Refer to 
<intxref refid = "S5JB0B8204001">Air Bag Diagnostic System Check</intxref>
 when checking SDM.
</ptxt>
</attention2>
<list1 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
Never attempt disassembly of SDM.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
When storing SDM, select a place where neither high temperature nor high humidity is anticipated and oil, water and dust are kept off.
</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname = "I5JB0A820001.swf" width = "88.000mm" height = "92.783mm" ver = "02" gw = "180" gh = "246"/>
</figure>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
If SDM has been dropped, replace it with a new one.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
If SDM installation part of floor was damaged, repair that part completely before reinstallation.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
All SDM and mounting bracket fasteners must be carefully torqued and the arrow must be pointed toward the front of the vehicle to ensure proper operation of the air bag system.
</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
</servinfosub>
<servinfosub id = "S5JB0B8200002002">
<title>
Live (Undeployed) Air Bag (Inflator) Modules
</title>
<ptxt>
Special care is necessary when handling and storing a live (undeployed) air bag (inflator) modules.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
The rapid gas generation produced during deployment of the air bag could cause the air bag (inflator) module, or an object in front of the air bag (inflator) module, to be thrown through the air in the unlikely event of an accidental deployment.
</ptxt>
<attention1>
<ptxt>
Never attempt to measure the resistance of the air bag (inflator) modules (driver, passenger and side of both sides and curtain of both sides). It is very dangerous as the electric current from the tester may deploy the air bag.
</ptxt>
</attention1>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname = "I5JB0A820002.swf" width = "88.000mm" height = "161.575mm" ver = "02" gw = "151" gh = "441"/>
</figure>
<list1 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
Never attempt disassembly of the air bag (inflator) modules.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
If any abnormality is found, be sure to replace it with new one as an assembly.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
When an abnormality is noted as existing in the live (undeployed) air bag (inflator) module, be sure to deploy it before discarding it.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
When grease, cleaning agent, oil, water, etc., got on the air bag (inflator) modules (driver, passenger, side of both sides and curtain of both sides), wipe it off immediately with a dry cloth.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
If air bag (inflator) module was dropped from a height of 90 cm (3 ft) or more, it should be replaced with a new one as an assembly.
</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
<attention1>
<list1 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
For handling and storage of a live air bag (inflator) module, select a place where the ambient temperature below 65 &#176;C (150 &#176;F), without high humidity and away from electric noise.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
When carrying a live air bag (inflator) module, make sure the bag opening is pointed away from you. In case of an accidental deployment, the bag will then deploy with minimal chance of injury. Never carry the air bag (inflator) module by the wires or connector on the underside of the module.
</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
<ptxt>
Otherwise, personal injury may result.
</ptxt>
</attention1>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname = "I5JB0A820003.swf" width = "88.000mm" height = "106.895mm" ver = "01" gw = "175" gh = "286"/>
</figure>
<attention1>
<ptxt>
When leaving or storing live air bag (inflator) module unattended on bench or other surface, always its bag (trim cover) facing up and away from surface.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
It is also prohibited to place anything on top of the trim cover and stack air bag (inflator) modules.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
This is necessary so that a free space is provided to allow the air bag to expand in the unlikely event of accidental deployment.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
Otherwise, personal injury may result.
</ptxt>
</attention1>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname = "I5JB0A820004.swf" width = "88.000mm" height = "57.858mm" ver = "02" gw = "212" gh = "147"/>
</figure>
</servinfosub>
<servinfosub id = "S5JB0B8200002003">
<title>
Live (Inactivated) Seat Belt Pretensioner
</title>
<ptxt>
Special care is necessary when handling and storing a live (inactivated) seat belt pretensioners.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
Also, when the seat belt pretensioners activate, gas is generated and the seat belt (1) is retracted into the retractor assembly (2) quickly.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
Note, therefore, that if they activate accidentally, the seat belt pretensioners and other object(s) around them may be thrown through the air.
</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname = "I3JA01820043.swf" width = "88.000mm" height = "36.099mm" ver = "01" gw = "142" gh = "85"/>
</figure>
<attention1>
<ptxt>
Never attempt to measure the resistance of the seat belt pretensioners. It is very dangerous as the electric current from the tester may activate pretensioner.
</ptxt>
</attention1>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname = "I5JB0A820005.swf" width = "88.000mm" height = "54.331mm" ver = "02" gw = "170" gh = "137"/>
</figure>
<list1 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
Never attempt to disassemble the seat belt pretensioners (retractor assembly).
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
If any abnormality is found, be sure to replace it with new one as an assembly.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
When an abnormality is noted as existing in the live (inactivated) seat belt pretensioner, be sure to activate it before discarding it.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
When grease, cleaning agent oil, water, etc., got on the seat belt pretensioners (retractor assembly), wipe it off immediately with a dry cloth.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
If seat belt pretensioner was dropped from a height of 30 cm (1 ft) or more, it should be replaced with a new one as an assembly.
</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
<attention1>
<list1 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
For handling and storage of a live seat belt pretensioner, select a place where the ambient temperature below 65 &#176;C (150 &#176;F), without high humidity and away from electric noise.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Never carry the seat belt pretensioner by webbing.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
When placing a live seat belt pretensioner on the workbench or other surface, be sure not to lay it with its exhaust hole (1) provided side facing down. It is also prohibited to put something on its face with an exhaust hole (1) or to put a seat belt pretensioner on top of another.
</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
<ptxt>
Otherwise, personal injury may result.
</ptxt>
</attention1>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname = "I2RH01820048.swf" width = "88.000mm" height = "42.689mm" ver = "01" gw = "164" gh = "104"/>
</figure>
</servinfosub>
<servinfosub id = "S5JB0B8200002004">
<title>
Deployed Air Bag (Inflator) Module and Activated Seat Belt Pretensioner
</title>
<attention1>
<list1 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
The air bag (inflator) module and seat belt pretensioner immediately after deployment&#x002F;activation is very hot. Wait for at least 30 minutes to cool it off before proceeding the work.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Do not apply water, oil, etc. to deployed air bag (inflator) module and to activate seat belt pretensioner.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
After an air bag (inflator) module has been deployed, the surface of the air bag may contain a powdery residue. This powder consists primarily of cornstarch (used to lubricate the bag as it inflates) and by-products of the chemical reaction. As with many service procedures, gloves and safety glasses should be worn.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Wash your hands with mild soap and water after completing the work.
</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
</attention1>
<ptxt>
Refer to the procedure described under 
<intxref refid = "S5JB0B8206018">Deployed Air Bag (Inflator) Module and Activated Seat Belt Pretensioner Disposal</intxref>
 for disposal.
</ptxt>
</servinfosub>
<servinfosub id = "S5JB0B8200002005">
<title>
Air Bag Wire Harness and Connector
</title>
<ptxt>
Air bag wire harness is included in main harness (1), instrument panel harness (2), floor harness (3) and seat harness (4). Air bag wire harness can be identified easily as the part of connector side wire harness is covered with a yellow protection tube. Be very careful when handling it.
</ptxt>
<list1 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
When an open in air bag wire harness, damaged wire harness, connector or terminal is found, replace wire harness, connectors and terminals as an assembly.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
When installing it, be careful so that the air bag wire harness is not caught or does not interfere with other parts.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Make sure air bag system grounding point (5) is clean and ground is securely fastened for optimum metal-to-metal contact. Poor grounding can cause intermittent problems that are difficult to diagnose.
</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname = "I5JB0A820006.swf" width = "88.000mm" height = "61.739mm" ver = "01" gw = "215" gh = "158"/>
</figure>
</item>
</list1>
</servinfosub>
</servinfo>
</servinfotype>
</configtype>
</servcat>
</section></manual></suzuki>
