<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="..\config\suzuki.xsl" ?><!DOCTYPE suzuki [<!ENTITY % sdatacharaents SYSTEM "..\config\sdatacharaents.txt">%sdatacharaents;]><suzuki><manual>
<section sectnbr = "00">
<servcat sctnbr = "00" scnbr = "00">
<configtype typenbr = "0">
<servinfotype sitcode = "0">
<servinfo servinfosgmlid = "S6JB0A0000007" svcinfotypenbr = "01" svcinfoqualnbr = "01" page = "2" supplyoff = "1" modify = "0">
<title>
Precautions for Electrical Circuit Service
</title>
<list1 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
When replacing a fuse, make sure to use a fuse of the specified capacity. Use of a fuse with a larger capacity will cause a damage to the electrical parts and a fire.
</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname = "I2RH01010038.swf" width = "88.000mm" height = "49.984mm" ver = "01" gw = "150" gh = "125"/>
</figure>
</item>
<c-change/>
<item>
<ptxt>
When disconnecting and connecting coupler, make sure to turn ignition switch OFF, or electronic parts may get damaged.
</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname = "I2RH01010039.swf" width = "88.000mm" height = "57.138mm" ver = "01" gw = "193" gh = "145"/>
</figure>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
When disconnecting connectors, never pull the wiring harness. Unlock the connector lock first and then pull them apart by holding connectors themselves.
</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname = "I2RH01010040.swf" width = "88.000mm" height = "48.503mm" ver = "01" gw = "153" gh = "120"/>
</figure>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
When connecting connectors, also hold connectors and put them together until they lock securely (a click is heard).
</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname = "I2RH01010041.swf" width = "88.000mm" height = "41.094mm" ver = "01" gw = "162" gh = "99"/>
</figure>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
When installing the wiring harness, fix it with clamps so that no slack is left.
</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname = "I2RH01010042.swf" width = "88.000mm" height = "40.882mm" ver = "01" gw = "149" gh = "99"/>
</figure>
</item>
<c-change/>
<item>
<ptxt>
When installing vehicle parts, be careful so that the wiring harness is not interfered with or caught by any other part.
</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname = "I2RH01010043.swf" width = "88.000mm" height = "43.084mm" ver = "01" gw = "143" gh = "105"/>
</figure>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
To avoid damage to the harness, protect its part which may contact against a part forming a sharp angle by winding tape or the like around it.
</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname = "I2RH01010044.swf" width = "88.000mm" height = "36.395mm" ver = "01" gw = "151" gh = "86"/>
</figure>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Be careful not to touch the electrical terminals of parts which use microcomputers (e.g. electronic control unit like as ECM, PCM, P&#x002F;S controller, etc.). The static electricity from your body can damage these parts.
</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname = "I3RM0A000004.swf" width = "88.000mm" height = "48.079mm" ver = "01" gw = "168" gh = "119"/>
</figure>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Never connect any tester (voltmeter, ohmmeter, or whatever) to electronic control unit when its coupler is disconnected. Attempt to do it may cause damage to it.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Never connect an ohmmeter to electronic control unit with its coupler connected to it. Attempt to do it may cause damage to electronic control unit and sensors.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Be sure to use a specified voltmeter &#x002F; ohmmeter. Otherwise, accurate measurements may not be obtained or personal injury may result. If not specified, use a voltmeter with high impedance (M &#937;&#x002F;V minimum) or a digital type voltmeter.
</ptxt>
</item>
<c-change/>
<item>
<ptxt>
When taking measurements at electrical connectors using a tester probe, be sure to insert the probe (2) from the wire harness side (backside) of the connector (1).
</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname = "I2RH01010046.swf" width = "88.000mm" height = "41.814mm" ver = "01" gw = "151" gh = "102"/>
</figure>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
When connecting meter probe (2) from terminal side of coupler (1) because it can&#8217;t be connected from harness side, use extra care not to bend male terminal of coupler of force its female terminal open for connection.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
In case of such coupler as shown connect probe as shown to avoid opening female terminal.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
Never connect probe where male terminal is supposed to fit.
</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname = "I2RH01010047.swf" width = "88.000mm" height = "48.079mm" ver = "01" gw = "174" gh = "119"/>
</figure>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
When checking connection of terminals, check its male half for bend and female half for excessive opening and both for locking (looseness), corrosion, dust, etc.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Before measuring voltage at each terminal, check to make sure that battery voltage is 11 V or higher. Such terminal voltage check at low battery voltage will lead to erroneous diagnosis.
</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname = "I2RH01010048.swf" width = "88.000mm" height = "51.000mm" ver = "01" gw = "90" gh = "128"/>
</figure>
</item>
</list1>
</servinfo>
</servinfotype>
</configtype>
</servcat>
</section></manual></suzuki>
