<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="..\config\suzuki.xsl" ?><!DOCTYPE suzuki [<!ENTITY % sdatacharaents SYSTEM "..\config\sdatacharaents.txt">%sdatacharaents;]><suzuki><manual>
<section sectnbr = "1A">
<servcat sctnbr = "01" scnbr = "01">
<configtype typenbr = "2">
<servinfotype sitcode = "1">
<servinfo servinfosgmlid = "S6JB0A1121006" svcinfotypenbr = "03" svcinfoqualnbr = "01" page = "2" supplyoff = "1" modify = "0">
<title>
Diesel Particulate Filter Regeneration Description
</title>
<ptxt>
As Diesel Particulate Filter is a device to trap the diesel particulate (PM), it is necessary that the accumulated PM is burned and diesel particulate filter regenerated.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
There are three ways to regenerate diesel particulate filter.
</ptxt>
<list1 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
&#8220;Natural regeneration&#8221; by catalysis and exhaust gas temperature
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
&#8220;Forced regeneration&#8221; by post-injection
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
&#8220;After-sales regeneration&#8221; by using SUZUKI scan tool
</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
<ptxt>
And, here is the mechanism to regenerate diesel particulate filter.
</ptxt>
<list1 type = "ordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
Diesel particulate filter, trapping PM, carries out &#8220;Natural regeneration&#8221; according to the driving condition. The driver will not find it.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
ECM consistently monitors the exhaust gas temperature, injection quantity, driving time, vehicle speed, PM mass etc. In case of the long-time idling and traffic jam at low speed that cause lowering the exhaust gas temperature, PM is accumulated gradually.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
When &#8220;Natural regeneration&#8221; becomes insufficient (PM mass exceeds 25 g), ECM will perform &#8220;Forced regeneration&#8221; by the post-injection at the point of appropriate driving condition. The post-injection will heat the exhaust gas temperature to enable &#8220;Forced regeneration&#8221;. In this situation, any warning indicator will not come on. Therefore, the driver will not recognize that &#8220;Forced regeneration&#8221; is performed.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
If &#8220;Forced regeneration&#8221; is interrupted by the engine stop, long-time idling and traffic jam at low speed that do not keep the specified exhaust gas temperature, ECM will memorize it as &#8220;Regeneration failure&#8221;. When the &#8220;regeneration failure&#8221; number (5 times) or PM mass reach at the specified conditions (PM mass exceeds 42 g), ECM will find it as &#8220;impossible to regenerate by diesel particulate filter itself and incapable of continuing the driving&#8221; and ask the driver for a help. This is &#8220;Speed request&#8221; announced to the driver by diesel particulate filter warning light (1) in combination meter. Then, the driver will be asked to increase the vehicle speed more than 75 km&#x002F;h (47 MPH) on the average for heating the exhaust gas temperature. If the regeneration is completed by &#8220;natural regeneration&#8221; or &#8220;Forced regeneration&#8221; when accumulating &#8220;regeneration failure&#8221;, the accumulation of &#8220;regeneration failure&#8221; will be reset.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
After the driver fulfills &#8220;speed request&#8221; for the regeneration and PM mass falls to the specified amount (5 ~ 8 g), the regeneration will complete and diesel particulate filter warning light be turned OFF. It will take about 20 minutes to complete the regeneration if the regeneration driving is performed properly. During the regeneration driving, &#8220;Forced regeneration&#8221; will go simultaneously to hasten the increase of exhaust gas temperature and shorten the time of regeneration. When the engine stops before diesel particulate filter warning light is turned OFF, PM mass that should be decreased will be calculated at starting the engine next time. At that time, if PM mass does not fall to the specified amount, diesel particulate filter warning light will come on again and the vehicle continue to ask the driver for regeneration driving.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
If the regeneration driving is not achieved and diesel particulate filter becomes almost clogged while &#8220;Speed request&#8221; is on, injection warning light (Gravity 1 Fault) (2) in combination meter will come on. Also, to prevent diesel particulate filter from melting and cracking, ECM will take following actions;
</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
EGR (Exhaust Gas Recirculation) will be cut off to avoid generating the extra PM.
</ptxt>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
&#8220;Forced regeneration&#8221; function will stop.
</ptxt>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Driving performance will be limited by lowering the engine torque to avoid &#8220;Natural regeneration&#8221;.
</ptxt>
</s1>
<ptxt>
Therefore, the driver will recognize the malfunction of diesel particulate filter.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
In this situation, &#8220;After-sales regeneration&#8221; using SUZUKI scan tool will be necessary or diesel particulate filter has to be replaced in the worst case.
</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname = "I5JB0B110016.swf" width = "88.000mm" height = "49.745mm" ver = "01" gw = "198" gh = "124"/>
</figure>
</servinfo>
</servinfotype>
</configtype>
</servcat>
</section></manual></suzuki>
