<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="..\config\suzuki.xsl" ?><!DOCTYPE suzuki [<!ENTITY % sdatacharaents SYSTEM "..\config\sdatacharaents.txt">%sdatacharaents;]><suzuki><manual>
<section sectnbr = "1A">
<servcat sctnbr = "01" scnbr = "01">
<configtype typenbr = "2">
<servinfotype sitcode = "0">
<servinfo servinfosgmlid = "S6JB0A1120002" svcinfotypenbr = "01" svcinfoqualnbr = "01" page = "2" supplyoff = "1" modify = "0">
<title>
Precautions in Diagnosing Trouble
</title>
<list1 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
Don&#8217;t disconnect couplers from ECM, battery cable from battery, ECM ground wire harness from engine or main fuse before confirming diagnostic information (DTC) stored in ECM memory.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Diagnostic information stored in ECM memory can be cleared as well as checked by using SUZUKI scan tool or OBD generic scan tool. Before using scan tool, read its Operator&#8217;s (Instruction) Manual carefully to have good understanding as to what functions are available and how to use it.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Be sure to read 
<intxref refid = "S6JB0A0000007">Precautions for Electrical Circuit Service</intxref>
 before inspection and observe what is written there.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Replacement of the ECM
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
Before replacement of the ECM, save the data of vehicle specification (injector calibration code, EGR &#x002F; Inlet throttle valve data register and Diesel PF data register) into SUZUKI scan tool from ECM according to procedure described in 
<intxref refid = "S6JB0A1321001">Description of ECM Registration:For Diesel Engine Model</intxref>
.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
ECM registration:
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
If ECM is replaced, register vehicle specification (fuel injector calibration code, key verification code for immobilizer system) into ECM referring to 
<intxref refid = "S6JB0A1321001">Description of ECM Registration:For Diesel Engine Model</intxref>
.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Communication of ECM, BCM, combination meter, ABS or ESP&#174; control module, immobilizer control module, 4WD control module, keyless start control module and steering angle sensor (ESP&#174; model) is established by CAN (Controller Area Network). (For more detail of CAN communication for ECM, refer to 
<intxref refid = "S6JB0A1121005">CAN Communication System Description:For Diesel Engine Model</intxref>
).
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
Therefore, handle CAN communication line with care referring to 
<intxref refid = "S6JB0A0000007">Precautions for Electrical Circuit Service</intxref>
.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Immobilizer transponder code registration after replacing ECM
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
When ECM is replaced with new one or with another one, make sure to register immobilizer transponder code to ECM correctly according to 
<intxref refid = "S6JB0AA326003">Procedure after ECM Replacement:For Diesel Engine Model</intxref>
.
</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
</servinfo>
</servinfotype>
</configtype>
</servcat>
</section></manual></suzuki>
