<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="..\config\suzuki.xsl" ?><!DOCTYPE suzuki [<!ENTITY % sdatacharaents SYSTEM "..\config\sdatacharaents.txt">%sdatacharaents;]><suzuki><manual>
<section sectnbr = "7B">
<servcat sctnbr = "07" scnbr = "02">
<configtype typenbr = "0">
<servinfotype sitcode = "0">
<servinfo servinfosgmlid = "S6JB0A7200003" svcinfotypenbr = "01" svcinfoqualnbr = "01" page = "2" supplyoff = "1" modify = "0">
<title>
Precautions in Diagnosing Trouble
</title>
<list1 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
Do not disconnect connector from HVAC control module, battery cable from battery, or main fuse before reading diagnostic information stored in HVAC control module memory.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
When diagnosing vehicle indoors, sunload sensor has to be lighted over vertically with an incandescent lamp. Otherwise, DTC is detected even if sunload sensor is normal.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Diagnostic information (diagnostic trouble code) stored in HVAC control module can be checked by display of HVAC control module. Also, it can be checked by using SUZUKI scan tool. Before checking diagnostic information (diagnostic trouble code), read this manual and operator&#8217;s manual for SUZUKI scan tool to know how to read diagnostic information (diagnostic trouble code).
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
When trouble is diagnosed using diagnostic information (diagnostic trouble code) on display of HVAC control module, keep in your mind that each diagnostic information (diagnostic trouble code) has priority, and only diagnostic information (diagnostic trouble code) which has the highest priority is indicated. Therefore, after troubleshooting the malfunction, make sure if there exists any other diagnostic information (diagnostic trouble code).
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
After troubleshooting some trouble, DTC can be stored in HVAC control module memory as history DTC.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Be sure to read &#8220;Precautions for Electrical Circuit Service&#8221; before inspection.
</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
</servinfo>
</servinfotype>
</configtype>
</servcat>
</section></manual></suzuki>
