<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="..\config\suzuki.xsl" ?><!DOCTYPE suzuki [<!ENTITY % sdatacharaents SYSTEM "..\config\sdatacharaents.txt">%sdatacharaents;]><suzuki><manual>
<section sectnbr = "7B">
<servcat sctnbr = "07" scnbr = "02">
<configtype typenbr = "0">
<servinfotype sitcode = "1">
<servinfo servinfosgmlid = "S6JB0A7201004" svcinfotypenbr = "03" svcinfoqualnbr = "01" page = "2" supplyoff = "1" modify = "0">
<title>
HVAC Control Module Operation Description
</title>
<servinfosub id = "S6JB0A7201004001">
<title>
Temperature Control
</title>
<ptxt>
HVAC control module calculates the target temperature control door position based on signals from the temperature selector, inside air temperature sensor, outside air temperature sensor and sunload sensor and controls the temperature control actuator so that the current position of the temperature control door matches its target position.
</ptxt>
</servinfosub>
<servinfosub id = "S6JB0A7201004002">
<title>
Fan Speed Control
</title>
<ptxt>
HVAC control module calculates the target blower fan speed based on signals from the temperature selector, inside air temperature sensor, outside air temperature sensor and sunload sensor, compares it with the current blower fan speed inputted from the blower motor controller to control the current blower fan speed to the target level.
</ptxt>
</servinfosub>
<servinfosub id = "S6JB0A7201004003">
<title>
Air Flow Outlet Control
</title>
<ptxt>
HVAC control module calculates the target temperature control door position based on signals from the temperature selector, inside air temperature sensor, outside air temperature sensor and sunload sensor. Using thus obtained target temperature control door position, it further calculates the target air flow control door position and controls the air flow control actuator so that the current air flow control door position becomes the target position.
</ptxt>
</servinfosub>
<servinfosub id = "S6JB0A7201004004">
<title>
Air Intake Position Control
</title>
<ptxt>
HVAC control module determines the air intake position based on signals from the temperature selector, inside air temperature sensor, outside air temperature sensor and sunload sensor and controls the air intake actuator.
</ptxt>
</servinfosub>
</servinfo>
</servinfotype>
</configtype>
</servcat>
</section></manual></suzuki>
