<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="..\config\suzuki.xsl" ?><!DOCTYPE suzuki [<!ENTITY % sdatacharaents SYSTEM "..\config\sdatacharaents.txt">%sdatacharaents;]><suzuki><manual>
<section sectnbr = "8B">
<servcat sctnbr = "08" scnbr = "02">
<configtype typenbr = "0">
<servinfotype sitcode = "4">
<servinfo servinfosgmlid = "S5JB0A8204001" svcinfotypenbr = "06" svcinfoqualnbr = "01" page = "2" supplyoff = "1" modify = "0">
<title>
Air Bag Diagnostic System Check
</title>
<attention1>
<ptxt>
To avoid deployment when troubleshooting the air bag system, do not use electrical test equipment such as a battery powered or AC powered voltmeter, ohmmeter, etc., or any type of electrical equipment other than that specified in this manual. Do not use a non-powered probe type tester.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
Instructions in this manual must be followed carefully, otherwise personal injury may result.
</ptxt>
</attention1>
<attention2>
<ptxt>
The order in which DTCs are diagnosed is very important. Failure to diagnose the DTCs in the order specified may result in extended diagnostic time, incorrect diagnosis and incorrect parts replacement.
</ptxt>
</attention2>
<ptxt>
The diagnostic procedures used are designed to find and repair air bag system malfunctions.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
To get the best results, it is important to use the diagnostic flow and follow the sequence in the following.
</ptxt>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Perform the 
<intxref refid = "S5JB0A8204002">Air Bag Diagnostic System Check Flow</intxref>
.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
(The 
<intxref refid = "S5JB0A8204002">Air Bag Diagnostic System Check Flow</intxref>
 must be the starting point of any air bag system diagnosis.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
The 
<intxref refid = "S5JB0A8204002">Air Bag Diagnostic System Check Flow</intxref>
 checks for proper &#8220;AIR BAG&#8221; warning lamp operation through &#8220;AIR BAG&#8221; warning lamp and whether air bag DTCs exist.)
</ptxt>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Refer to the proper diagnostic flow as directed by the 
<intxref refid = "S5JB0A8204002">Air Bag Diagnostic System Check Flow</intxref>
.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
(The 
<intxref refid = "S5JB0A8204002">Air Bag Diagnostic System Check Flow</intxref>
 will lead you to the correct flow to diagnose any air bag system malfunctions. Bypassing these procedures may result in extended diagnostic time, incorrect diagnosis and incorrect parts replacement.)
</ptxt>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Repeat the 
<intxref refid = "S5JB0A8204002">Air Bag Diagnostic System Check Flow</intxref>
 after any repair or diagnostic procedures have been performed.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
(Performing the 
<intxref refid = "S5JB0A8204002">Air Bag Diagnostic System Check Flow</intxref>
 after all repair or diagnostic procedures will ensure that the repair has been made correctly and that no other malfunctions exist.)
</ptxt>
</s1>
</servinfo>
</servinfotype>
</configtype>
</servcat>
</section></manual></suzuki>
