<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="..\config\suzuki.xsl" ?><!DOCTYPE suzuki [<!ENTITY % sdatacharaents SYSTEM "..\config\sdatacharaents.txt">%sdatacharaents;]><suzuki><manual>
<section sectnbr = "1J">
<servcat sctnbr = "01" scnbr = "10">
<configtype typenbr = "0">
<servinfotype sitcode = "6">
<servinfo servinfosgmlid = "S5JB0A1A06004" svcinfotypenbr = "08" svcinfoqualnbr = "03" page = "2" supplyoff = "1" modify = "0">
<title>
Jump Starting in Case of Emergency
</title>
<servinfosub id = "S5JB0A1A06004001">
<title>
With Auxiliary (Booster) Battery
</title>
<attention2>
<ptxt>
If vehicle is manual transmission model and has a catalytic converter, do not push or tow it to start. Damage to its emission system and&#x002F;or to other parts may result.
</ptxt>
</attention2>
<ptxt>
Both booster and discharged battery should be treated carefully when using jumper cables. Follow the procedure outlined as follows, being careful not to cause sparks.
</ptxt>
<attention1>
<list1 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
Departure from these conditions or procedure described as follows could result in:
</ptxt>
</item>
<list2 type = "ordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
Serious personal injury (particularly to eyes) or property damage from such causes as battery explosion, battery acid, or electrical burns.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Damage to electronic components of either vehicle.
</ptxt>
</item>
</list2>
<item>
<ptxt>
Never expose battery to open flame or electric spark. Batteries generate gas which is flammable and explosive.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Remove rings, watches, and other jewelry. Wear approved eye protection.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Do not allow battery fluid to contact eyes, skin, fabrics, or painted surface as fluid is a corrosive acid. Flush any contacted area with water immediately and thoroughly.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Be careful so that metal tools or jumper cables do not contact positive battery terminal (or metal in contact with it) and any other metal on vehicle, because a short circuit could occur.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Batteries should always be kept out of reach of children.
</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
</attention1>
<c-change/>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Set parking brake and place automatic transmission in PARK (NEUTRAL on manual transmission).
</ptxt>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Turn OFF ignition switch, turn OFF lights and all other electrical loads.
</ptxt>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Check built-in indicator (if equipped). If it is clear or light yellow, replace the battery.
</ptxt>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Attach end of one jumper cable to positive terminal of booster battery and the other end of the same cable to positive terminal of discharged battery. (Use 12-volt battery only to jump start engine).
</ptxt>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Attach one end of the remaining negative cable to negative terminal of booster battery, and the other end to a solid engine ground (such as exhaust manifold) at least 45 cm (18 in.) away from battery of vehicle being started.
</ptxt>
<attention1>
<ptxt>
Do not connect negative cable directly to negative terminal of dead battery.
</ptxt>
</attention1>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Start engine of vehicle with booster battery and turn off electrical accessories. Then start engine of the vehicle with discharged battery.
</ptxt>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Disconnect jumper cable in the exact reverse order.
</ptxt>
</s1>
</servinfosub>
<servinfosub id = "S5JB0A1A06004002">
<title>
With Charging Equipment
</title>
<attention2>
<ptxt>
When jump starting engine with charging equipment, be sure equipment used is 12-volt and negative ground. Do not use 24-volt charging equipment. Using such equipment can cause serious damage to electrical system or electronic parts.
</ptxt>
</attention2>
</servinfosub>
</servinfo>
</servinfotype>
</configtype>
</servcat>
</section></manual></suzuki>
