<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="..\config\suzuki.xsl" ?><!DOCTYPE suzuki [<!ENTITY % sdatacharaents SYSTEM "..\config\sdatacharaents.txt">%sdatacharaents;]><suzuki><manual>
<section sectnbr = "9B">
<servcat sctnbr = "09" scnbr = "02">
<configtype typenbr = "0">
<servinfotype sitcode = "0">
<servinfo servinfosgmlid = "S5JB0A9200001" svcinfotypenbr = "01" svcinfoqualnbr = "01" supplyoff = "1" modify = "0">
<title>
Precautions for Discharge Headlight Service (If Equipped)
</title>
<attention1>
<list1 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
Do not touch igniter or ballast when lighting switch is at &#8220;HEAD&#8221; position to avoid possible electric shock.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Do not measure voltage or resistance with tester connected to output connector of ballast or igniter to avoid possible electric shock.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Do not perform work where exposed to water including rain or with wet hands to avoid possible electric shock.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Disassembling igniter or ballast is strictly prohibited as it may cause an electric shock.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Before inspecting or repairing discharge headlight or its peripheral parts, make sure that lighting switch is at OFF position and battery is disconnected at negative terminal to avoid possible electrical shock.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Do not set lighting switch to &#8220;HEAD&#8221; position with connector disconnected or any part removed to avoid possible electric shock.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Do not touch glass surface of headlight bulb. Oil or grease attached on it may not only make bulb service life shorter but also cause bulb to burst when lighting switch is turned on.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Mercury, metal iodide and xenon gas are sealed in discharge headlight bulb. Be sure to dispose of used discharge headlight bulb properly according to applicable rules or regulations.
</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
</attention1>
</servinfo>
</servinfotype>
</configtype>
</servcat>
</section></manual></suzuki>
