<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="..\config\suzuki.xsl" ?><!DOCTYPE suzuki [<!ENTITY % sdatacharaents SYSTEM "..\config\sdatacharaents.txt">%sdatacharaents;]><suzuki><manual>
<section sectnbr = "10E">
<servcat sctnbr = "10" scnbr = "05">
<configtype typenbr = "0">
<servinfotype sitcode = "6">
<servinfo servinfosgmlid = "S5JB0AA506009" svcinfotypenbr = "08" svcinfoqualnbr = "03" page = "2" supplyoff = "1" modify = "0">
<title>
Registration Procedure for Remote Controller ID Code
</title>
<attention3>
<list1 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
It is possible to register up to 4 remote controllers in keyless start control module.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Setting keyless start control module to ID code registration mode of remote controller will erase all remote controller ID codes that have been registered in keyless start control module.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
Therefore, when registering remote controller ID codes in keyless start control module, have all of those to be registered ready and execute their registration at the same time.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
When registration of more than four remote controller ID codes is attempted, the oldest remote controller ID code will be erased and that inputted after the fourth one will be registered.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
When keyless start control module which was used in another vehicle has been installed, it is necessary to perform both registration of remote controller ID code in keyless start control module and registration of ignition key transponder code in ECM. For registration procedure of ignition key transponder code, refer to 
<intxref refid = "S5JB0AA306002">Registration of the Ignition Key</intxref>
.
</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
</attention3>
<c-change/>
<ptxt>
If remote controller or keyless start control module is replaced with a new one or additional remote controller is necessary, register ID code(s) of remote controller.
</ptxt>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Sit in driver seat and close all doors.
</ptxt>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Check that door lock of driver seat is unlocked.
</ptxt>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Insert ignition key (1) into ignition key cylinder.
</ptxt>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Perform Steps a) through f) described below within 25 seconds after Step 3).
</ptxt>
<s2>
<ptxt>
First push manual door lock switch (2) toward lock side (3) and then push it toward unlock side (4).
</ptxt>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>
Repeat Step a) 2 more times.
</ptxt>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>
Push lock side of manual door lock switch.
</ptxt>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>
Remove ignition key from ignition key cylinder once and then insert it again.
</ptxt>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>
Repeat Step d) 3 more times.
</ptxt>
</s2>
<s2>
<ptxt>
Start engine and wait for 3 seconds.
</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname = "I5JB0AA50023.swf" width = "88.000mm" height = "116.420mm" ver = "03" gw = "186" gh = "313"/>
</figure>
<attention3>
<ptxt>
When 60 seconds elapse after engine is started, the above process to enter registration mode will be cancelled. Therefore, be sure to proceed to the next step within 60 seconds.
</ptxt>
</attention3>
</s2>
</s1>
<c-change/>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Turn ignition switch to OFF position.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
When ignition switch is turned to OFF position, buzzer sounds twice and door lock is activated from lock position to unlock position. This operation indicates that keyless start control module has entered registration mode.
</ptxt>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
Push lock or unlock button of remote controller within 30 seconds after Step 5) to be registered.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
When lock or unlock button of remote controller is pushed, buzzer sounds twice, door lock is activated to lock position and then to unlock position. This operation indicates that remote controller ID code has been registered in keyless start control module.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
If an additional remote controller needs to be registered, repeat the procedure of Step 6) within 30 seconds after Step 5).
</ptxt>
</s1>
<s1>
<ptxt>
To end registration mode, remove ignition key from ignition key cylinder or turn it to ON position.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
If engine start function of keyless start system does not work after registration, check ECM if DTC P1615 is detected. If it is detected, go to 
<intxref refid = "S5JB0AA304014">DTC P1615: Steering Lock Unit Communication Error (for Vehicle with Keyless Start System)</intxref>
. If it is not detected, perform registration procedure again.
</ptxt>
</s1>
</servinfo>
</servinfotype>
</configtype>
</servcat>
</section></manual></suzuki>
