<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="..\config\suzuki.xsl" ?><!DOCTYPE suzuki [<!ENTITY % sdatacharaents SYSTEM "..\config\sdatacharaents.txt">%sdatacharaents;]><suzuki><manual>
<section sectnbr = "8B">
<servcat sctnbr = "08" scnbr = "02">
<configtype typenbr = "0">
<servinfotype sitcode = "8">
<servinfo servinfosgmlid = "S5JB0A8208001" svcinfotypenbr = "11" svcinfoqualnbr = "01" page = "2" supplyoff = "1" modify = "0">
<title>
Use of Special Tools
</title>
<attention1>
<ptxt>
To avoid deployment when troubleshooting the air bag system, do not use electrical test equipment such as a battery powered or AC powered voltmeter, ohmmeter, etc., or any type of electrical equipment other than that specified. Do not use a non-powered probe type tester.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
Instructions must be followed carefully, otherwise personal injury may result.
</ptxt>
</attention1>
<ptxt>
You should be familiar with the tools listed under the heading &#8220;Special Tool&#8221;. You should be able to measure voltage and resistance. You should be familiar with proper use of a scan tool such as Air Bag Driver &#x002F; Passenger Load Tool, Connector Test Adapter Kit and the Digital Multimeter.
</ptxt>
<servicetool>
<servicetoolitem id = "L8B0196">
<s-part>
(A)
</s-part>
<s-number num = "09932-76010">
09932&#8211;76010
</s-number>
<ptxt>
(Connector Test Adapter Kit)
</ptxt>
</servicetoolitem>
</servicetool>
<c-change/>
<ptxt>
This must be used whenever a diagnostic procedure requests checking or probing a terminal.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
Using the appropriate adapter in the special tool will ensure that no damage to the terminal will occur from the multimeter probe, such as spreading or bending.
</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname = "I5JB0A820107.swf" width = "88.000mm" height = "48.333mm" ver = "01" gw = "206" gh = "120"/>
</figure>
<c-change/>
<ptxt>
The adapter (1) will also give an idea of whether or not contact tension is sufficient, helping to find an open or intermittent open due to poor terminal contact. An SDM short bar release tool (2) is included in the connector test adapter kit. Inserting it into the SDM connector (3) will releases the shorting bar.
</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname = "I5JB0A820108.swf" width = "88.000mm" height = "63.856mm" ver = "01" gw = "117" gh = "164"/>
</figure>
<servicetool>
<servicetoolitem id = "L8B0197">
<s-part>
(B)
</s-part>
<s-number num = "09932-75010">
09932&#8211;75010
</s-number>
<ptxt>
(Air bag driver &#x002F; passenger load tool)
</ptxt>
</servicetoolitem>
</servicetool>
<ptxt>
This tool is used as a diagnostic aid and safety device to prevent inadvertent air bag (inflator) module deployment.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
The load tool has three connectors attached to its case which are electrically functional and serve as resistive load substitutions.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
No more than two connectors are used at any time.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
One of connectors (&#8220;STEERING WHEEL&#8221;) is used to substitute the load of the followings.
</ptxt>
<list1 type = "unordered">
<item>
<ptxt>
Driver air bag (inflator) module when it is connected at the top of the column to the contact coil assembly.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Passenger air bag (inflator) module when it is connected to the air bag harness connector in instrument panel harness for passenger air bag (inflator) module.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Each of driver and passenger seat belt pretensioners when it is connected to air bag harness connector in instrument panel harness for driver and passenger seat belt pretensioners.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Side-air bag (inflator) module when it is connected to the floor harness connector for side-air bag (inflator) module.
</ptxt>
</item>
<item>
<ptxt>
Side curtain-air bag (inflator) module when it is connected to the floor harness connector for side curtain-air bag (inflator) module.
</ptxt>
</item>
</list1>
<c-change/>
<ptxt>
Another connector (&#8220;BASE OF COLUMN&#8221;) is used to substitute the load of the driver air bag (inflator) module and the contact coil assembly when it is connected at the base of the column to the air bag wire harness.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
The third connector (&#8220;PASSENGER INFLATOR&#8221;) is not used.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
By substituting the resistance of the load tool when called for, a determination can be made as to whether an inflator circuit component is causing system malfunction and which component is causing the malfunction.
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
The load tool should be used only when specifically called for in the diagnostic procedures.
</ptxt>
<figure>
<graphic graphicname = "I1JA01820004.swf" width = "88.000mm" height = "67.468mm" ver = "01" gw = "173" gh = "174"/>
<callout>
<table frame = "all" colsep = "1" rowsep = "1">
<tgroup cols = "2" colsep = "1" rowsep = "1">
<colspec colnum = "1" colname = "1" colwidth = "0.236in"/>
<colspec colnum = "2" colname = "2" colwidth = "3.228in"/>
<tbody>
<row rowsep = "1">
<entry colname = "1" border-top = "1" border-bottom = "1" border-left = "1" border-right = "0" align = "right">
<ptxt>
1.
</ptxt>
</entry>
<entry colname = "2" border-top = "1" border-bottom = "1" border-left = "0" border-right = "1">
<ptxt>
Connector for contact coil and driver air bag (inflator) module 
</ptxt>
<ptxt>
(Located near the base of the steering column)
</ptxt>
</entry>
</row>
<row rowsep = "1">
<entry colname = "1" border-top = "1" border-bottom = "1" border-left = "1" border-right = "0" align = "right">
<ptxt>
2.
</ptxt>
</entry>
<entry colname = "2" border-top = "1" border-bottom = "1" border-left = "0" border-right = "1">
<ptxt>
Connector for driver, passenger air bag (inflator) module, side-air bag (inflator) module and driver and passenger seat belt pretensioners
</ptxt>
</entry>
</row>
<row rowsep = "0">
<entry colname = "1" border-top = "1" border-bottom = "1" border-left = "1" border-right = "0" align = "right">
<ptxt>
3.
</ptxt>
</entry>
<entry colname = "2" border-top = "1" border-bottom = "1" border-left = "0" border-right = "1">
<ptxt>
Not used
</ptxt>
</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</callout>
</figure>
</servinfo>
</servinfotype>
</configtype>
</servcat>
</section></manual></suzuki>
